Okay. My turn, my turn. Um, I got one.
Giliranku. Aku bisa ini.
Great, but can you make it
Bisakah kau buat...
a little more challenging this time?
Agar sedikit lebih menantang?
Okay. Check this out.
Baiklah. Dengar ini.
I spy with my little eye...
Aku melihat dengan mataku.
something yellow...
Warnanya kuning..
and round, and it eats dots.
Bulat, dan makan titik-titik.
Seriously, Ralph?
Kau serius, Ralph?
Yeah, seriously. You're never gonna get it.
Ya. Kau tidak akan bisa menjawabnya.
Well, obviously, it's Pac-Man.
Sudah jelas itu Pac-Man.
No, that's not...
Itu tidak...
Why is that obvious?
Kenapa itu jelas?
Name one other thing in this whole arcade
Coba sebutkan makhluk yang ada di Arcade ini.
that is yellow and round and eats dots.
Berwarna kuning, bulat, dan makan titik.
I can name two things.
Ada dua.
Ms. Pac-Man and Baby Pac-Man.
Nona Pac-Man dan Bayi Pac-Man.
Boom! I accept your apology.
Aku menerima maafmu.
Yeah, you're right. Okay. But was it Pac-Man?
Kau benar. Tapi jawabannya Pac-Man?
Yeah, you got me.
Ya, kau benar.
Knew it. All right, riddle me this...
Sudah kuduga. Coba tebak ini..
do you or do you not think that Zangief waxes?
Apakah Zangief mencukur bulunya?
No way. Look at the guy. He looks like a yeti.
Mustahil. Lihat dia. Dia seperti Yeti.
I don't know.
Entahlah.
I mean, if the fur were confined to his chest,
Jika bulunya hanya ada di dada..
I might agree...
Mungkin aku setuju.
but look at those two very specific
Tapi lihatlah dua..
tuffets of shin hair...
Bulu di ujung kakinya.
poking out of his boots.
Yang keluar dari sepatunya.
That does not just happen, Ralph. That is a choice.
Itu bukan alami, Ralph. Itu buatan.
You're totally right, kid.
Kau benar, Nak.
He's baby smooth everywhere else.
Bagian tubuh yang lainnya mulus.
I rest my case.
Sudah disimpulkan.
My mind is blown!
Aku takjub!
Let's go get a root beer.
Ayo minum Root Beer.
Okay, let's see what you got, kid.
Kita lihat kemampuanmu, Nak.
Nice one. Okay.
Bagus.
I think I got one in the chamber.
Aku ada satu.
- Gross. - Thank you.
Jorok. Terima kasih.
Hey, wanna sneak into Tron?
Mau menyelinap ke Tron?
Doesn't that game have a virus?
Bukankah game itu bervirus?
No. I'm sure they fixed it.
Kurasa mereka sudah memperbaikinya.
I'm gonna beat my speed record!
Aku akan kalahkan rekor cepatku!
Hey, wait for me!
Tunggu aku!
Ralph.
Ralph.
Yeah?
Ya?
I don't think they fixed the game.
Kurasa game-nya belum benar.
Uh... No.
Benar.
Help!
Tolong!
Hey, Tron!
Hei, Tron!
Tronny!
Tronny!
Help!
Tolong!
Do you realize
Apa kau sadar..
we're basically just, like, zeroes and ones...
Kalau kita ini hanya angka 0 dan 1.
floating around the universe like tiny specks of dust?
Yang mengambang di semesta seperti debu?
Like, doesn't the very nature
Apakah...
of our existence make you wonder...
Keberadaan kita membuatmu berpikir.
if there's more to life than this?
Kalau ada kehidupan yang lain di luar sana?
Why would I wonder if there's more to life
Kenapa aku harus memikirkan ada kehidupan yang lain.
when the life I got is perfect?
Saat hidupku ini sudah sempurna?
I mean, sure. Doesn't look so hot on paper.
Memang hidupku tidak kelihatan bagus.
I'm just a bad guy from some old video game
Aku hanya penjahat di video game.
who wrecks a building.
Yang menghancurkan gedung.
And yeah, for 27 years,
Selama 27 tahun.
I was a total zero without any friends.
Aku pecundang tanpa teman.
But now, I got a best friend...
Tapi sekarang, aku punya sahabat.
who just happens to be
Yang menjadi..
the coolest kid in the whole arcade.
Anak terkeren di Arcade ini.
Aw, thanks, pal.
Terima kasih, Kawan.
Watch this.
Lihat ini.
Home run!
Home run!
All right, let's go watch the sunrise.
Ayo lihat matahari terbit.
Are you really saying
Maksudmu...
there's not one single, solitary thing...
Tidak ada satupun.
about your life that you would change?
Di hidupmu yang ingin kau ubah?
Well, think about it.
Coba kau pikir.
You and me get to goof off all night long.
Kita berdua keluyuran tengah malam.
Litwak shows up, we go to work, we put in our hours.
Saat Litwak datang, kita pergi bekerja.
Then the arcade closes
Lalu Arcade tutup...
and we get to do it all over again.
Dan kita mengulanginya lagi.
The only thing I might do different in that scenario...
Aktivitas berbeda yang bisa kulakukan.
would be not having to go to work.
Adalah kalau aku tidak bekerja.
Other than that, I wouldn't change a thing.
Selain itu, aku tidak mau mengubah apapun.
Hey, where'd our sunrise go?
Di mana matahari terbitnya?
All right, let's get you plugged in.
Coba kucolok.
That's a plug-in alert.
Itu peringatan colokan.
Litwak hasn't plugged in a new game in forever.
Sudah lama Litwak tidak pasang game baru.
- Let's go see what it is! - Yeah!
Ayo kita lihat! Ya!
Excuse us. Excuse us. Minor emergency.
Permisi. Darurat kecil.
Hey, Felix, Calhoun, what's getting plugged in?
Felix, Calhoun, apa yang dipasang?
Well, Ralph, Sonic thinks
Ralph, Sonic pikir...
it's gonna be a new pinball machine.
Itu sebuah mesin pinball baru.
What do you think, lady love?
Bagaimana menurutmu, Sayang?
I'll bet you a shiny nickel it's a blood pressure machine.
Pasti itu mesin tensi.
- Kids love those things. - Ooh.
Anak-anak suka itu.
Please be a racing game.
Kumohon, game balapan baru.
"Whiffee"? Or, "Wifey"?
"Whiffee" atau "Wifey"?
Well, it's either wiffle ball, or an arranged marriage game.
Entah itu bola wiffle atau game nikah-nikahan.
It's actually pronounced "Wi-Fi," Ralph.
Ucapan yang benar adalah "Wi-Fi", Ralph.
Yeah, that's what I said.
Itu kataku.
And Wi-Fi is the Internet...
Wi-Fi adalah Internet...
which is an online community
Yaitu komunitas online.
where human beings go to shop...
Di mana manusia pergi berbelanja.
and play games and socialize.
Bermain game dan bersosialisasi.
Ooh, fun!
Menyenangkan!
Oh, no, it is not.
Tidak.
That sign right there says "Wi-Fi."
Tanda itu bertuliskan "Wi-Fi".
What it should say is "Die-Fi."
Tapi arti yang sebenarnya adalah "Die-Fi".
That's a little humor there.
Itu lelucon.
But seriously, the Internet is nothing to laugh at.
Tapi Internet bukan untuk ditertawakan.
It is new, it is different,
Itu baru, berbeda..
and therefore we should fear it.
Dan kita harus takut.
So keep out, for Pete's sake, and get to work.
Jadi menjauhlah dan siap untuk bekerja.
The arcade's about to open.
Arcade sebentar lagi buka.
Figures, we finally get something new plugged in...
Akhirnya ada sebuah mesin baru.
and we're not even allowed to go in there.
Dan kita dilarang masuk.
Totally not fair.
Sangat tidak adil.
A new racing game would've been cool.
Game balapan baru pasti seru.
Something wrong with your game?
Memangnya game-mu kenapa?
No, no.
Tidak.
It's just every bonus level's been unlocked.
Semua level bonus sudah terbuka.
I know every shortcut.
Aku sudah tahu semua jalan pintas.
Man, I'd kill for even just a new track.
Aku sangat ingin lintasan baru.
New track? You already got, like, three choices.
Lintasan baru? Kau sudah punya tiga pilihan lintasan.
Yeah, I know, but don't you ever wish
Aku tahu, tapi kau tidak berharap..
something new and different...
Ada yang baru dan beda.
would happen in your game?
Di dalam game-mu?
Nope.
Tidak.
Really? Well, agree to disagree.
Sungguh? Setuju untuk berbeda pendapat.
Wait, I don't wanna disagree.
Aku tidak mau berbeda pendapat.
No, no. It's just a fancy way to say
Tidak. Itu hanya ungkapan...
we don't have to argue about it.
Kalau kita tidak perlu berdebat.
We're arguing? I don't wanna argue.
Kita berdebat? Aku tidak mau debat.
Relax. Stop making it a thing.
Tenang. Jangan permasalahkan.
Go to work. I'll see you tonight, stench vessel.
Bekerjalah. Sampai nanti malam, pria bau.
All right.
Baik.
She wants a new track, I'll give her a new track.
Dia mau lintasan baru, akan kuberikan.
Come on, Nafisa! Let's play Sugar Rush!
Ayo, Nafisa! Kita main Sugar Rush!
Pick Vanellope, Swati.
Pilih Vanellope, Swati.
She's got the best superpower.
Kekuatan supernya adalah yang terbaik.
Yeah, the glitch. I love her.
Ya, Glitch. Aku suka dia.
Drivers,
Para pembalap
start your engines.
Nyalakan mesin kalian.
You're gonna lose today, Princess.
Kau akan kalah, Tuan Putri.
While, yes, I am technically a princess, Taffyta...
Aku memang seorang putri, Taffyta.
I'd rather you just think of me as plain old Vanellope...
Pikirkan saja aku sebagai Vanellope lama.
the racer who's about to kick your butt.
Pembalap yang akan mengalahkanmu.
Three, two, one, go!
Tiga, dua, satu, mulai!
And pardon me, excuse me, coming through.
Permisi, mau lewat.
And one, two, three gumballs right on cue.
Satu, dua, tiga bola permen. Tepat hitungan.
Yeah, I love it when she glitches.
Aku suka saat dia Glitch.
Excuse me. I must have fallen asleep.
Permisi. Aku pasti tertidur.
Oh, fun. I'm winning.
Menyenangkan. Aku menang.
Vanellope takes a huge lead.
Vanellope jauh memimpin.
No one's gonna catch her now.
Tidak akan ada yang bisa mendahuluinya.
She's gonna love this.
Dia pasti suka ini.
Right on time.
Tepat waktu.
What?
Apa?
"Looking for something new...
"Mencari sesuatu yang baru."
"and different?
"Dan berbeda?"
"Then take this track."
"Pilih lintasan ini."
Oh, Ralph, you old son-of-a-gun.
Ternyata Ralph.
I'd say I got a little time for a detour.
Sepertinya aku akan sempat berputar.
Hey, look, I think I unlocked a new track.
Kurasa aku membuka lintasan baru.
Never seen that before.
Aku tidak pernah melihat ini sebelumnya.
This is awesome!
Ini luar biasa!
Hey, thanks, Ralph!
Terima kasih, Ralph!
You're welcome!
Sama-sama!
Get back up on the track, Swati.
Kembali ke lintasan, Swati.
You're going to lose.
Kau akan kalah.
I can't. It's like it's driving itself.
Aku tidak bisa. Dia mengemudi sendiri.
What is wrong with this thing?
Benda ini kenapa?
What?
Apa?
No, no!
Tidak!
Kid!
Nak!
Oh, kid, I'm so sorry, are you okay?
Nak, maafkan aku. Kau tidak apa?
Oh, my gosh.
Astaga.
What an amazing track!
Lintasan yang hebat!
Thank you, Ralph! Thank you, thank you, thank you!
Terima kasih, Ralph!
You're welcome!
Sama-sama.
You know I take my duty as your hero very seriously.
Aku menganggap penting peran pahlawanku.
Wait a minute.
Tunggu.
You took a serious doody where?
Peran pahlawan apa?
Vanellope, get up here.
Vanellope, kemarilah.
We have a situation.
Kita ada masalah.
Mr. Litwak, the Vanellope racer wasn't working...
Tn. Litwak, Vanellope tidak normal.
and I think maybe I turned the wheel too hard.
Dan mungkin setirnya kuputar terlalu keras.
- Whoa. - I'm real sorry.
Maafkan aku.
It's okay, Swati.
Tidak apa, Swati.
I think I can get it back on there pretty easy.
Aku bisa memasangnya kembali.
- What did you do, Ralph? - Nothing.
Apa yang sudah kau perbuat, Ralph? Tak ada.
Leave him alone.
Jangan ganggu dia.
He was just trying to make the game more exciting.
Dia mencoba membuat game menjadi menarik.
Yeah, why don't you relax, Taffyta? Litwak will fix it.
Tenanglah, Taffyta. Litwak akan memperbaiki ini.
All right, on you...
Baik. Coba...
Okay. Still not a problem.
Masih bukan masalah.
He'll just order a new part.
Dia akan pesan setir baru.
Well, I'd order a new part...
Aku mau pesan setir baru.
but the company that made Sugar Rush
Tapi perusahaan pembuat Sugar Rush.
went out of business years ago.
Sudah tutup sejak lama.
I can try to find one on the Internet.
Aku bisa cari di Internet.
- Good idea. - Oh, me too.
Ide bagus. Aku juga.
Good luck, that'll be like finding a needle in a...
Itu seperti mencari jarum di..
I found one! On ebay!
Ketemu! Di ebay!
Really? How about that?
Coba kulihat.
See? Those kids have it under control.
Anak-anak itu bisa mengatasinya.
They're just gonna get another wheel from the eboy.
Mereka akan beli setir di eboy.
Are you kidding me? How much?
Kau bercanda? Berapa?
That's more than this game makes in a year.
Itu lebih dari penghasilan setahun game ini.
Aw, I hate to say it,
Aku benci mengatakannya..
but my salvage guy is coming on Friday...
Tapi temanku akan datang Jumat ini.
and it might be time to sell Sugar Rush for parts.
Dan sepertinya ini sudah waktunya untuk menjual Sugar Rush.
- Aww. - Where's he going?
Dia pergi ke mana?
Litwak's gonna unplug the game.
Litwak akan mencabut gamenya.
Get out of here! Go, scram, let's go, run!
Pergi dari sini! Lari!
- Let's go! - Run!
Ayo!
Gangway!
Minggir!
Stop it! No running!
Jangan berlari!
What are you people doing out of your game,
Kenapa kalian keluar dari game?
The arcade is open!
Arcade masih buka!
Sugar Rush is getting unplugged.
Sugar Rush akan dicabut.
- We're homeless! - Yeah, yeah, we're homeless!
Kita tuna wisma! Ya, kita tuna wisma!
Oh, what are we going to do?
Kita harus apa?
Y'all, calm down, calm down. Get a hold of yourselves.
Tenang. Sabar dulu.
I don't want to be gameless.
Aku tidak mau menjadi tuna wisma.
An unplugging. Good Lord.
Ya ampun.
I haven't seen this many gameless characters
Aku tidak pernah lihat karakter buangan sebanyak ini.
since Space Invaders went down.
Sejak Space Invaders dihentikan.
Where are we gonna live?
Di mana kami akan tinggal?
Well, you can stay here until the arcade closes, I guess...
Kalian bisa tinggal disini sampai Arcade tutup.
and then we'll figure out
Lalu kita akan pikirkan.
where the heck we're gonna put you all.
Di mana kalian akan tinggal.
Okay.
Baik.
Here we go.
Ini dia.
I raided Gene's fridge.
Aku menyerbu kulkas Gene.
Good news, he's got pie.
Kabar baiknya, dia punya pai.
Took a bunch of his pillows and junk, too.
Aku juga ambil bantal dan lainnya.
I'm thinking we make a fort up here, or like a yurt.
Kita bisa buat benteng atau tenda.
Or we could take these pillows...
Kita bisa ambil bantal ini.
If we stack them right,
Jika disusun..
we can make an igloo out of pillows.
Kita bisa buat rumah igloo dari bantal.
Like a pillow igloo. Pigloo. Pigloo!
Seperti igloo bantal. Igban!
So what do you think, kid?
Bagaimana, Nak?
Fort, yurt, or the obvious best choice, pigloo?
Benteng, tenda, atau igban?
I can't believe I don't have a game anymore.
Aku tidak percaya sudah tidak punya game.
I mean, like, what am I gonna do all day?
Aku harus melakukan apa selama seharian?
What? Come on, are you kidding?
Kau bercanda?
You sleep in, you do no work,
Kau tidur, tidak bekerja..
then you go to Tapper's with me every night.
Lalu ke Tapper's denganku tiap malam.
I've literally just described paradise.
Itu surga.
But I loved my game.
Tapi aku suka game-ku.
Oh, come on.
Ayolah.
You were just bellyaching about the tracks
Kau mengeluh soal lintasannya..
being too easy.
Terlalu mudah.
No, that doesn't mean I didn't love it.
Bukan berarti aku tidak suka gamenya.
Yeah, sure, it was kind of predictable...
Game itu memang mudah ditebak.
but still I never really knew what might happen in a race.
Tapi aku tidak tahu yang terjadi saat balapan.
And it's that, it's that feeling,
Perasaan itu...
that not-knowing-what's- coming-next feeling.
Yang tidak tahu apa yang terjadi ke depannya.
That's the stuff. That feels like life to me.
Itu intinya. Itu seperti hidup bagiku.
And if I'm not a racer, Ralph...
Jika aku bukan pembalap, Ralph.
what am I?
Aku harus jadi apa?
Well, you're my best friend.
Kau sahabatku.
That's not enough.
Itu tidak cukup.
Hey.
Hei.
No, I just...
Tidak, aku...
I'm sorry, I know I'm being weird.
Maaf, aku tahu tingkahku aneh.
I think maybe I just need to be alone right now.
Kurasa aku butuh waktu sendiri.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I'll meet you over at Tapper's in a little while, I guess.
Sampai jumpa di Tapper's.
If you want.
Kalau kau mau.
All right, now...
Baiklah.
we found some good homes
Kami menemukan rumah bagus.
for so many of our chums from Sugar Rush...
Untuk teman kita dari Sugar Rush.
and we're just hoping a few more of you
Dan kami harap kalian.
will open your doors...
Bisa membuka pintu..
and your hearts to those in need.
Dan hati kalian untuk yang membutuhkan.
Well, I suppose that large green olive
Kurasa zaitun hijau besar itu.
will fit in nicely with my decor.
Cocok dengan dekorasiku.
I'm a sour ball.
Aku permen asam.
Well, beggars can't be choosers, can they?
Tuna wisma tidak bisa milih-milih, 'kan?
Come along, condiment.
Ayo, bumbu dapur.
Mm-kay.
Baik.
Marvelous. That just leaves the racers.
Luar biasa. Tinggal para pembalap.
We're, like, adorable.
Kami menggemaskan.
You sure are.
Pastinya.
So, any takers?
Ada yang mau ambil?
Anyone?
Ada?
Felix, I know we've never once talked about
Felix, aku tahu kita pernah bicarakan.
having a family before, but...
Untuk berkeluarga, tapi...
I know, it feels like the kind of thing
Aku tahu, rasanya seperti.
you just jump into with both feet...
Langsung masuk...
and nary a plan.
Dan tidak merencanakannya.
Felix and I will give them sanctuary.
Aku dan Felix akan beri mereka tempat tinggal.
Can I get a quick word with you two?
Bisa kita bicara?
Look, I get it.
Aku mengerti.
You've been married six years,
Kalian sudah menikah selama 6 tahun.
you're looking to spice things up...
Kalian ingin bumbu pernikahan.
but trust me, adopting 15 children
Tapi percayalah, mengadopsi 15 anak.
is the wrong kind of spice.
Adalah bumbu yang salah.
Those things are basically feral.
Mereka liar.
Pardon me, sir, but those youngsters are lambs.
Maaf, tapi anak-anak itu adalah domba.
Lost little lambs in need of two kind, caring shepherds.
Domba kecil yang butuh dua gembala.
That's right.
Itu benar.
Besides, how hard can parenting be?
Apa sulitnya jadi orangtua?
You treat the child like your best friend...
Perlakukan anak-anak seperti sahabat.
you give them everything they want...
Berikan keinginan mereka.
and you just love their little socks off.
Dan kau menyayangi mereka.
Right, Tammy?
Benar, Tammy?
Darn-tootin'.
Benar sekali.
Come and get it.
Ambillah.
Get your own candle.
Cari lilin sendiri.
Hey, Mom, why does your lame TV
Ibu, kenapa TV-nya..
only have one channel?
Cuma ada satu saluran?
Well, hate to say I told ya...
Sudah kubilang.
Hey, Tapper?
Hei, Tapper...
No, Ralph. I haven't seen Vanellope.
Tidak, Ralph. Aku tidak lihat Vanellope.
Not since the last time you asked me 30 seconds ago.
Kau sudah tanyakan itu 30 detik yang lalu.
Sorry. I'm just worried about her.
Maaf. Aku mencemaskannya.
She's glitching like crazy, and acting super insecure.
Dia sering Glitch dan tingkahnya sangat gugup.
Oh. And get this, she said...
Dan dia bilang...
being friends with me wasn't enough for her.
Berteman denganku tidak cukup untuknya.
Not enough? I'm a great friend!
Tidak cukup? Aku teman yang baik!
Right, Tapper? Right?
Benar, Tapper?
I'm sorry. Who's acting insecure?
Maaf. Siapa yang tingkahnya gugup?
Ralph, come on.
Ralph, ayolah.
The kid just lost her game. Give her a break.
Dia baru saja kehilangan game. Beri dia sedikit waktu.
There you are... Oh.
Kau datang.
Hey, Ralph.
Hei, Ralph.
Hey, Felix. Since when do you drink root beer?
Hei, Felix. Sejak kapan kau minum Root Beer?
Since tonight.
Sejak malam ini.
Yeah, I hear you, buddy.
Aku mengerti, Kawan.
Hey, listen. This one was supposed to be for Vanellope.
Minuman ini untuk Vanellope.
I guess you can have it.
Tapi kau bisa meminumnya.
Doesn't look like she's coming.
Sepertinya dia tidak datang.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
You know, I can't help but think
Aku terus berpikir.
this whole mess is somehow...
Kekacauan ini.
partially my fault.
Sebagian adalah salahku.
It figures. Just when my life was perfect.
Sudah kutebak. Saat hidupku sempurna.
Mine was, too.
Hidupku juga.
But, hey, now I'm a father of 15.
Sekarang aku menjadi ayah dari 15 anak.
Isn't that just a blessing?
Bukankah itu berkah?
Eeeee-oh-boy!
Eeeee-oh-boy!
Wait. What'd you say, Felix?
Apa katamu, Felix?
Um, isn't that just a blessing?
Bukankah itu berkah?
No, the weird sound thing.
Bukan, suara aneh itu.
Oh. Eeeee-oh-boy?
Eeeee-oh-boy?
Yeah. Eee-oh...
Ya. Eee-oh...
Sorry, say it again?
Katakan lagi?
- Eeeee-oh-boy. - Eeeee-oh-boy!
Eeeee-oh-boy. Eeeee-oh-boy!
- Eee-oh-boy! - Eee-boy! Say it again?
Eee-oh-boy! Eee-boy! Katakan lagi.
- Eeeee-oh-boy! - Eeeee-oh-boy.
Eeeee-oh-boy! Eeeee-oh-boy.
- Eeeee-oh-boy... - eboy! eboy! eboy!
Eeeee-oh-boy... Eboy!
- eboy? eboy? - eboy.
Eboy? Eboy.
Yeah.
Ya.
Um, what are you getting at there, Ralph?
Apa maksudmu, Ralph?
That kid out in the arcade
Anak di Arcade...
said there was a steering wheel part...
Bilang ada setir.
on the Internet, it's something called eboy or...
Di Internet, namanya eboy atau..
ebay! That's it, it was ebay!
Ebay! Namanya ebay!
Ralph, are you thinking about
Ralph, kau berpikir...
going to the Internet and finding that part?
Akan pergi ke Internet dan mencari setir?
Getting that part's the only thing
Setir itu adalah satu-satunya.
that's gonna fix the game and that's the only thing
Cara untuk memperbaiki game dan...
that's gonna make Vanellope happy again.
Membuat Vanellope bahagia lagi.
And if Sugar Rush is fixed,
Jika Sugar Rush di perbaiki.
all those lovable scamps living in my house...
Semua anak nakal yang tinggal di rumahku.
and destroying my sanity
Dan menghancurkan kewarasanku.
will have homes of their own again!
Akan punya rumah sendiri lagi!
Ralph, this is an important mission. A noble mission!
Ralph, ini misi penting. Misi mulia!
I will cover for you.
Aku akan membantumu.
Thanks, pal.
Terima kasih.
Ralph, what about your tab? You owe me for the root beer.
Ralph, tagihanmu bagaimana? Kau berutang Root Beer.
Oh, Felix is gonna cover for me.
Felix yang bayar.
Drinks on the house, everybody! Felix is paying.
Minuman gratis!
Eeeee-oh-boy.
Eeeee-oh-boy.
Ralph, what is wrong with you?
Ralph, kau kenapa?
Start churning butter
Bersiaplah...
and put on your church shoes, little sister...
Dan pasang sepatumu, Adikku.
'cause we're about to blast off!
Karena kita akan meluncur!
What are you even talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Oh, we're going to the Internet.
Kita akan ke Internet.
What?
Apa?
Yeah, to find the part to fix your game.
Mencari setir untuk perbaiki game-mu.
No way!
Yang benar!
Yeah, I probably should've just said,
Mungkin aku hanya perlu bilang.
"We're going to the Internet." We're going to the Internet!
"Kita akan ke Internet." Kita akan ke Internet!
Yeah, we are!
Benar!
Hey, Surge, are we glad to see you.
Surge, bagus kau ada disini.
We want to report some malfeasance
Kami ingin melaporkan pelanggaran.
over by the Whac-A-Mole.
Di samping Whac-A-Mole.
Yeah, we saw some undesirables
Kami melihat...
causing a real donnybrook over there.
Kekacauan di sana.
Oh, heck no. Not on my watch.
Itu tidak bisa dibiarkan.
Appreciate the tip.
Kuhargai bantuan kalian.
So, all we gotta do is find this eboy place.
Kita tinggal mencari lokasi eboy.
- Ebay. - Right, ebay.
Ebay. Benar.
So we go there, get the steering wheel...
Kita ke sana, beli setirnya..
we have it delivered to Litwak before Friday.
Antar ke Litwak sebelum hari Jumat.
He'll fix your game.
Dia akan memperbaiki game-mu.
Everything goes back to the way it was.
Semua kembali normal.
Boom! Happily ever after.
Bahagia selamanya.
This is a shockingly sound,
Idemu ternyata...
well-thought-out idea for you, Ralph.
Bagus juga, Ralph.
No offense.
Jangan tersinggung.
I know. And none taken.
Aku tidak tersinggung.
Ooh, here it comes.
Ini dia.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls...
Tuan dan Nyonya, lelaki dan wanita.
I give you the Internet!
Kupersembahkan Internet!
The Internet is not nearly as impressive
Internet tidak semenarik..
as how Sonic described it.
Seperti yang dikatakan Sonic.
Yeah, I gotta admit, I'm underwhelmed.
Aku kecewa.
Where do you think they keep their ebay?
Di mana mereka menyimpan ebay?
Beats me.
Entahlah.
Hello, anybody here?
Halo, apa ada orang?
Anyone? Hello!
Halo!
We're looking for ebay!
Kami mencari ebay!
Ooh. Did you hear that, kid? Sweet echo.
Kau dengar itu? Gemanya bagus.
Check this out.
Dengar ini.
Okay, connect to network.
Sambung ke jaringan.
Bingo.
Dapat.
Password is "high score" with a zero instead of an "o."
Kata sandinya "high sc0re".
Yes.
Ya.
And we are online.
Dan kita online.
Ooh, Ralph, look.
Ralph, lihat.
Cool. Mood lighting.
Keren. Cahaya bagus.
Ahhh! That's a gremlin! Stay away! It's a gremlin!
Itu gremlin! Menjauhlah!
It looks like a tiny Mr. Litwak.
Itu seperti Tn. Litwalk kecil.
IP address 415-1037-483.
Alamat IP 415.1037.483.
Oh, cool! Come on, Ralph, let's follow him!
Keren! Ayo ikut dia, Ralph!
Hey, wait for me! Kid, come back! Wait!
Tunggu aku! Kembalilah!
Hey! Don't leave without me!
Jangan tinggalkan aku!
IP address 415-1037-483.
Alamat IP 415.1037.483.
Vanellope!
Vanellope!
I can't breathe. I don't fit.
Aku tidak bisa bernapas.
Yeah! Whoo!
Ya!
Kid!
Nak!
Ralph! Isn't this great?
Ini hebat, 'kan?
No, it is not!
Tidak!
No, no, no.
Tidak.
Sweet mother of monkey milk!
Ya ampun.
Kid, I don't think we're in Litwak's anymore.
Nak, kurasa kita sudah tidak di Litwak's lagi.
We most certainly are not, friendo.
Benar sekali, Kawan.
We are in the Internet! Come on, Ralph!
Kita di Internet! Ayo, Ralph!
Holy cow!
Ya ampun!
Look at all this stuff.
Lihat semua ini.
This is the most beautiful miracle I've ever seen.
Ini keajaiban terindah yang pernah kulihat.
But it's so big.
Tapi sangat besar.
It goes on forever and ever.
Tidak ada ujungnya.
How are we possibly gonna find
Bagaimana kita bisa...
ebay out there?
Temukan ebay?
Hey, kid. Kid, don't worry.
Nak, tenanglah.
I'm sure there's someone out here
Pasti ada seseorang...
who could give us directions. Oh!
Yang bisa beri tahu arahnya.
Look at that little egg guy.
Lihat pria telur itu.
He's got on one of those hats that smart people wear.
Dia memakai topi orang pintar.
I bet he could help us. Come on.
Pasti dia bisa membantu. Ayo.
Welcome back to the search bar, madam.
Selamat datang kembali di kotak pencarian, Nyonya.
I hope you were able to find
Kuharap kau bisa temukan...
a satisfactory breakfast burrito...
Sarapan burrito memuaskan.
based upon the search results I provided this morning.
Berdasarkan hasil pencarian tadi pagi.
What can KnowsMore help you find now?
Apa lagi yang bisa KnowsMore carikan?
Where can I find ballet...?
Di mana aku bisa temukan balet...
Ballet shoes? Ballet classes? Ballet folklorico?
Sepatu balet? Kelas balet? Cerita balet?
...tights?
Celana balet?
Girls' size small.
Ukuran kecil untuk wanita.
Oh, little Madeline's trying ballet now, is she?
Madeline kecil ingin mencoba balet, ya?
I hope this lasts longer than the soccer phase.
Kuharap lebih lama daripada sepakbola.
I found 23 million results
Aku temukan 23 juta hasil.
for ballet tights, girls' size small.
Untuk celana balet, ukuran kecil untuk wanita.
Isn't that interesting?
Itu menarik.
Redirecting to DesmondsTutus.com.
Mengarahkan ke DesmondsTutus.com.
They never say thank you.
Mereka tidak pernah berterima kasih.
Oh, hello, sir.
Halo, Pak.
Interesting, you don't seem to have a search history.
Kau belum punya sejarah pencarian.
Well, let's start one for you.
Mari mulai yang pertama.
What can KnowsMore help you find today?
Apa yang bisa KnowsMore carikan?
- Um... - Umbrella. Umbrage.
Um... Payung. Tersinggung.
- Umami. Uma Thurman. - No.
Umami. Uma Thurman. Bukan.
Noah's Ark. No Doubt. Nordstrom Rack.
Bahtera Nuh. No Doubt. Nordstrom Rack.
Err.
Err.
Ergonomics. Urban Outfitters. Urkel, played by Jaleel White.
Ergonomi. Urban Outfitters. Urkel, dimainkan oleh Jaleel White.
Looks like no one put Humpty Dumpty together again.
Sepertinya dia tahu banyak.
This guy's a little soft-boiled.
Otaknya sangat cepat.
I'm pretty sure he's just trying to
Aku yakin dia berusaha...
guess what you're gonna say.
Menebak perkataanmu.
Yes. I'm sorry,
Ya. Maaf.
but my autofill is a touch aggressive today.
Tapi autofill-ku sangat agresif hari ini.
Let me try. ebay Sugar Rush
Biar kucoba. Ebay Sugar Rush.
steering wheel.
Setir.
I only found one result for your query.
Ada satu hasil dari pertanyaanmu.
Hmm. Isn't that interesting?
Itu menarik.
What? How did you...?
Bagaimana kau...
Ah, the Internet's very intuitive.
Internet sangat intuitif.
Thank you, Mr. KnowsMore.
Terima kasih, Tn. KnowsMore.
Well, you're welcome.
Sama-sama.
Redirecting to ebay.
Mengarahkan ke ebay.
I like her. What a delightful girl.
Aku suka dia. Gadis yang menyenangkan.
Slow traffic will be fined for speeds
Lalu lintas akan lambat karena kecepatan.
less than three megabytes per second.
Kurang dari 3 MBps.
Wow, I guess we know where to go
Kurasa kita akan tahu arah.
if we ever need a pair of goggles.
Kalau punya kacamata.
There's a whole building full of them.
Gedungnya dipenuhi oleh itu.
Oh! There it is! ebay!
Itu dia! Ebay!
Ralph, we're really gonna do it.
Ralph, kita akan melakukannya.
We're actually gonna save my game.
Kita akan selamatkan game-ku.
Told you not to worry.
Sudah kubilang jangan cemas.
We just gotta keep our eyes on the prize and stay focused.
Tetap fokus ke tujuan kita.
Get rid of belly fat using this one weird trick.
Hilangkan lemak perut gunakan trik aneh ini.
Ooh! I love weird tricks.
Aku suka trik aneh.
Sassy housewives want to meet you.
Ibu rumah tangga ingin menemuimu.
They do?
Sungguh?
Congratulations, you're a winner!
Selamat, kau menang!
These ten child stars went to prison.
10 artis anak-anak ini dipenjara.
Number six will amaze you.
Nomor 6 akan membuatmu terkejut.
Ooh. That sounds interesting.
Itu menarik.
Wanna get rich playing video games?
Mau kaya dengan main video game?
Click here to find out how.
Klik di sini untuk tahu caranya.
Ralph, come on!
Ralph, ayo!
But there's a lot of cool stuff here.
Banyak hal keren di sini.
I'll be right here if you change your mind, brother.
Aku di sini kalau kau berubah pikiran.
Ooh, how about you, lady?
Bagaimana denganmu?
You wanna get rich playing video games?
Mau kaya dengan main video game?
Ladies and gentlemen, the next item up...
Para pengunjung, item selanjutnya...
a black velvet painting of a sorrowful kitten.
Lukisan kucing sedih berlatar hitam.
Bidding starts at 49.99.
Tawaran mulai dari 49.99.
850 for the beaver,
850 untuk berang-berang.
the beautifully taxidermied beaver...
Buatan yang diisi ahlinya.
...a gently used artificial hip...
Pinggul yang sudah terpakai...
and the bidding's open at $10. Do I hear 20?
Penawaran dibuka $10. Ada yang mau $20?
Do I hear 350? Who'll give me 350?
Siapa yang mau 350?
50, 50, 50 now.
50.
- Who'll give me 350? - 400!
Siapa mau 350? 400!
Going once, going twice and sold!
Satu, dua, dan terjual!
The tortilla chip shaped like
Kripik tortilla berbentuk...
international superstar Beyonce Knowles... goes for 400.
Beyonce terjual 400.
Yay! So happy.
Aku sangat senang.
Are you understanding how this game works?
Kau paham cara mainnya?
I think all you have to do is yell out the biggest number...
Kurasa cukup teriak angka tertinggi.
and then you win this stuff.
Lalu kau menang.
And I thought Qbert's game was weird.
Kukira game Qbert itu aneh.
Hey, kid, hop up here...
Nak, naiklah...
and see if you can tell
Dan coba lihat.
where they keep their steering wheels.
Di mana setirnya.
Uh, there's a bunch of
Ada banyak...
sports memberabilia.
Peralatan olahraga.
And big baby clothes called "lingerie."
Pakaian bayi besar namanya "lingerie".
- Huh. - Go to the right, move right.
Pindah ke kanan.
Oh. There's a row with a bunch of old video game junk!
Ada barisan barang video game lawas.
Oh, there it is! There it is! I see it!
Itu dia! Aku lihat!
Oh, someone else is trying to win it.
Ada yang mencoba menang.
Come on! Hurry, let's go!
Ayo! Cepat!
We got 275.
Ada yang mau 275.
And with 30 seconds left in the auction, we have 275.
Akan terjual 30 detik lagi.
Move! Move! Hey!
Minggir!
- That's ours! Out of the way! - Do I hear a three?
Itu punya kami! Ada yang mau 300?
- I'll give you three! - I got three!
Aku mau 300! Ada!
Can I get a 305? 305? Can I get a 3-5?
Mau 305?
- 305. - 305, can I get a 310?
305. Mau 310?
- Can you bid 310? - 310.
Kau bisa 310? 310.
- 315. - 320.
315. 320.
325.
325.
Oh, man, this guy is good.
Dia hebat.
He keeps coming up with numbers like it's nothing.
Dia mudah menyebut angka.
I have three-and-a-quarter. Do I hear 350?
Aku dapat 325. Ada yang mau 350?
- 350? 350? - Watch this.
350? Perhatikan ini.
1,000!
1.000!
We now have a bid of 1,000!
Tawaran sekarang 1.000!
Way to go, kid! That is a huge number.
Bagus, Nak. Itu angka yang besar.
- Thank you. - Check this out.
Terima kasih. Lihat ini.
15,000!
15.000!
15,000! Do I hear 15-5?
Ada yang mau 15.500?
15-fiver!
15.500!
- 16! - 17!
16.000! 17.000!
- 18! - 20!
18.000! 20.000!
- 23! - 25!
23.000! 25.000!
- 27! - 27 and one!
27.000! 27.001!
And sold! For 27,001...
Terjual seharga 27.001.
to the barefoot hobo
Kepada gelandangan.
in the broken overalls.
Dengan pakaian rusak.
Hey, that's me!
Itu aku!
- We won!
Kita menang!
Congratulations. Here's your voucher
Selamat. Ini voucher-mu.
for auction item 197324579.
Untuk item lelang 197324579.
Please take it to checkout for processing.
Mohon ke kasir untuk diproses.
So, we are set to ship
Kami akan kirim.
one Sugar Rush steering wheel...
Satu setir Sugar Rush.
Mmm-hmm. - ...to a Litwak's Family
Ke Litwak's Family FunLand.
FunLand in Los Aburridos, California.
Di Los Aburridos, California.
Yep!
Ya!
With expedited shipping,
Dengan pengiriman cepat.
that should arrive Wednesday morning.
Barang akan datang Rabu pagi.
That's two whole days before Litwak scraps your game.
Dua hari sebelum Litwak bongkar game-mu.
We're way ahead of schedule.
Kita sangat cepat.
We rule!
Kita hebat!
I'll just need a credit card number.
Aku butuh nomor kartu kredit.
Sorry, what's a credit card number?
Apa itu nomor kartu kredit?
A credit card number.
Nomor kartu kredit.
Number. Right. Uh, seven.
Baik. Tujuh.
Excuse me?
Apa?
Sorry, no. You're right, ridiculous. I meant 11.
Maaf, kau benar. Maksudku 11.
Those aren't credit card numbers.
Itu bukan nomor kartu kredit.
I'm pretty sure they are.
Aku yakin itu nomornya.
How exactly do you intend to pay for this item, sir?
Bagaimana kau akan bayar item ini, Tuan?
You owe $27,001.
Kau berutang $27.001.
What?
Apa?
Dollars? Dollars like money?
Uang dolar?
Yes, and if you don't have a credit card...
Ya, jika tidak punya kartu kredit.
we also accept PayPal, Venmo,
Kami juga menerima Paypal, Venmo.
ProPay, SquareCash and BuzzzyBucks.
ProPay, SquareCash dan BuzzzyBucks.
You're gonna laugh. Okay.
Kau akan tertawa.
So this big galoot, he left his wallet at home.
Dompetnya ketinggalan.
Yeah, yeah, I did leave my wallet at home,
Dompetku di rumah.
in my wallet room. And the door's locked.
Di ruangan dompet dan pintunya terkunci.
Look. If you don't pay within 24 hours...
Jika kau tidak bayar dalam 24 jam.
you will be in violation of the unpaid item policy...
Kau akan melanggar aturan item tidak dibayar.
you will forfeit the bid, and you will lose this item.
Tawaran hilang, dan kehilangan item ini.
Next!
Berikutnya!
Hey, buddy, you going to eboy?
Kawan, kau mau ke eboy?
Well, I got some free advice for you. Don't.
Aku punya saran. Jangan.
What a scam!
Dasar penipu!
We were so close, and we would have gotten...
Kita hampir mendapatkannya
Look, their signs aren't even real!
Papan mereka saja palsu!
What the heck? Dang Internet.
Apa-apaan? Internet bodoh.
Oh, man, oh, man, oh, man.
Ya ampun.
Hey, kid. What's going on? What's wrong?
Hei, Nak. Ada apa?
If I don't have a steering wheel,
Jika setirnya tidak ada..
I don't have a game, I'm gameless.
Aku tidak punya game.
There's only one steering wheel in the whole Internet...
Hanya ada satu setir di Internet.
and we blew our chance to get it. We blew it!
Dan kita mengacaukannya!
Hey, hey, hey, calm down.
Tenanglah.
We came here to save your game,
Kita ke sini untuk selamatkan game-mu.
and that's what we're gonna do.
Dan kita akan lakukan itu.
Right.
Baiklah.
- Okay? - Okay, yeah.
Paham? Ya.
There you go.
Itu dia.
Now look, all we got to do...
Kita harus...
is figure out a way to earn a little bit of moola.
Memikirkan bagaimana cara untuk mendapatkan uang.
We're video game characters, Ralph. We don't have moola.
Kita karakter game. Tidak punya uang.
Unless you can think of some magical way
Kecuali ada keajaiban.
to get rich playing video games.
Jadi kaya karena main game.
Wanna get rich playing video games?
Mau kaya dengan main video game?
Click right here to find out how.
Klik di sini untuk tahu caranya.
Back off, pop-up!
Mundur, pop-up!
Right this way, miss.
Sebelah sini, Nona.
Dang pop-up blockers.
Pemblokir pop-up bodoh.
Why does everybody gotta be so mean?
Kenapa semua orang sangat jahat?
Ooh! There he is! Oh, thank goodness you're still here!
Itu dia! Untung kau ada di sini!
Me and my friend here, we got 24 hours to make $27,001...
Kami ingin mendapatkan $27.001 dalam 24 jam.
or she loses her game.
Atau dia akan kehilangan gamenya.
Yeah, can you please tell us
Bisa kau beri tahu...
how to get rich playing video games?
Cara kaya dengan main game?
You bet!
Pasti!
Come on, click here, and I'll take you to my website.
Klik di sini dan kuarahkan ke situs web-ku.
You got an ample carriage there, buster.
Bawaanmu agak berat.
Causing a little drag.
Ada sedikit hambatan.
Sorry. You're getting close to the edge.
Maaf. Kau hampir di ujung.
Huh?
Apa?
You see the...? The edge. The edge!
Kau lihat. Ujungnya!
By the way, my name is JP Spamley...
Namaku JP Spamley.
and I'd like to welcome the both of you
Dan kusambut kalian.
to the Spamley family.
Di keluarga Spamley.
All right, step into my parlor.
Masuklah ke ruang tamuku.
This is your website?
Ini situs web-mu?
I know what you're thinking, not to worry.
Aku tahu kalian cemas, tenanglah.
My anti-virus guy was just here.
Teman anti virus-ku ada di sini.
Clean as a...
Bersih seperti...
Dang it!
Sial!
Oh, my gosh. That's embarrassing.
Astaga. Itu memalukan.
Anyway, I know it's a bit of a mess...
Situsku sedikit berantakan.
Hey, Gord!
Hei, Gord!
But I do have a system here, I really do.
Tapi aku punya sistem di sini.
If I can just find that... Gord!
Jika aku bisa temukan. Gord!
I just got to find this list.
Aku harus temukan daftarnya.
Oh, there you are.
Itu dia.
These guys are looking to get rich playing video games.
Mereka ingin kaya dengan main game.
What do you got for them, partner?
Kau punya apa, rekan?
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
"Fishwife's amulet, Wizard Quest, three dollars."
"Jimat Fishwife, Wizard Quest $3."
"Foxhole hammer,
"Palu"
"Zombie Crusades, five dollars"?
"Zombie Crusades $5"?
Now, those there are
Itu...
some of your more commonplace, low-dollar items.
Beberapa barang biasa yang murah.
Can you back up a sec, Mr. Spamley?
Bisa bicara, Tn. Spamley?
Um, you're saying if we find
Jika kami temukan...
the Golden Cleats
Sepatu Emas.
from Pro League Soccer...
Dari Pro League Soccer.
we find those and bring them back here to you...
Dan kami berikan padamu.
then a human being in the real world will pay us $15?
Maka manusia asli akan membayar kami $15?
Yes, ma'am.
Ya, Nona.
Welcome to the exciting world of loot hunting.
Selamat datang di perburuan loot.
Folks go into games...
Orang-orang bermain.
they harvest the most coveted items...
Memanen item terkenal.
and they sell them on my website
Dan dijual di situsku.
to the highest bidder. Ha-ha?
Ke penawar tertinggi.
Okay, but here's the thing...
Baik, tapi masalahnya.
we need like a buttload of money.
Kami butuh banyak uang.
So, do you have any more lucrative items, maybe?
Ada item yang lebih menguntungkan?
Gord!
Gord!
Oh, there you are.
Kau di sana.
Thank you, buddy. You're such a nice guy.
Terima kasih, Kawan. Pria baik.
Is $40,000 lucrative enough for you?
Apa $40.000 cukup menguntungkan?
It's more than enough.
Itu lebih dari cukup.
I got a guy in Des Moines, Iowa...
Ada orang di Des Moines, Iowa.
who will pay 40 grand for Shank's car...
Yang akan bayar $40.000 untuk mobil Shank.
from a game called Slaughter Race.
Dari game Slaughter Race.
A racing game?
Game balapan?
That's right. Slaughter Race is the most popular
Benar. Slaughter Race adalah game online.
online racing game out there.
Terpopuler di Internet.
However, it is wicked dangerous.
Tapi sangat bahaya.
We ain't afraid of danger.
Kami tidak takut bahaya.
This kid's the best racer in the whole world.
Dia pembalap terbaik di dunia.
We'll get you that car, no problemo.
Kami akan dapatkan mobil itu.
Slaughter Race! Enter at your own risk.
Slaughter Race! Terima risikonya.
Okay, this game is kind of amazing.
Game ini menakjubkan.
Meh, the attention to detail is pretty impressive.
Detailnya mengesankan.
I don't think I've ever been in a game
Aku tidak pernah masuk game.
with smog before.
Dengan kabut asap sebelumnya.
- Nice kitty. Nice kitty. - Easy, boy. Easy.
Kucing pintar. Tenang.
Let's just find Shank's car and get outta here.
Ayo kita cari mobil Shank dan pergi dari sini.
Agreed.
Setuju.
- Look. Look. - Whoa!
Lihat.
There it is.
Itu dia.
That car is gorgeous.
Mobilnya indah.
No wonder it's worth so much.
Pantas harganya mahal.
Aw, sugar.
Sial.
- Players. They beat us to it. - Aw.
Para pemain. Mereka duluan.
31 hours of continuous gameplay...
Bermain 31 jam.
and we've finally found Shank's car.
Dan kita menemukan mobil Shank.
Let's jack this ride.
Ayo curi mobil ini.
Oh, yeah, DirtySocks, it's on.
Kita mulai, DirtySocks.
Jim! Jimmy?
Jimmy?
You're not playing that horrible game again, are you?
Kau tidak main game buruk itu lagi, 'kan?
No, Grandma!
Tidak, Nenek!
I'm doing my homework.
Aku sedang kerjakan PR.
Okay, like I said...
Seperti kataku..
Let's jack this ride.
Ayo curi mobil ini.
While the cat was away, these mice tried to play.
Selagi kucing pergi, tikus ini bermain.
Hey, I think that might be Shank.
Kurasa itu Shank.
Listen up, mice...
Dengar, tikus..
anyone who tries to play with this cat's ride
Siapapun yang main dengan mobil kucing.
is gonna get got.
Akan tertangkap.
You're going down, Shank.
Kau akan kalah, Shank.
Pyro. Give those punks the works.
Pyro, beri mereka pelajaran.
With pleasure.
Dengan senang hati.
End of the road!
Akhir perjalanan!
Gosh dang it! Now we gotta start all over.
Sial! Kita harus mulai lagi.
Ralph, maybe...
Ralph, mungkin...
Hey, where are you going?
Kau mau ke mana?
I am scared.
Aku takut.
If we get burned up in here,
Jika kita dibakar..
that's it, we're dead, we're gone.
Kita mati.
So, I think we should get outta here right now.
Kita harus pergi sekarang.
No, wait, wait. I have an idea.
Tunggu. Aku ada ide.
Hey, Shank?
Hei, Shank?
What's up, Pyro?
Ada apa, Pyro?
Um, do you ever reckon we're going a bit too hard
Kau sadar kita terlalu keras.
on the players?
Pada para pemain?
Honestly, no, I don't.
Terus terang, tidak.
Of course, I have empathy for players like DirtySocks537
Tentu aku kasihan pada pemain seperti DirtySocks537...
and BabeRaham_Linkin...
Dan BabeRaham_Linkin.
but if we just let them win,
Tapi jika mereka dibiarkan menang.
where's the life lesson? You know?
Di mana pelajaran hidupnya?
- Mmm. - Yeah, but to Pyro's point...
Tapi maksud Pyro.
I mean, those players work so hard to get here.
Para pemain sudah berusaha keras untuk sampai ke sini.
I hear you, Felony...
Aku paham, Felony.
but imagine a game without challenges.
Tapi bayangkan game tanpa tantangan.
The same predictable thing every single time...
Semua bisa ditebak.
who wants that?
Siapa yang mau?
Shank's right.
Shank benar.
I just saw a really insightful TED talk...
Aku melihat presentasi TED Talk.
and I can't really remember what the guy said.
Dan aku tidak ingat perkataan orang itu.
It was more about how he made me feel.
Intinya perkataannya menyentuhku.
But I think, ultimately, the point was...
Tapi kurasa intinya.
I honor your journeys, guys.
Kuhargai perjalanan kalian.
And we honor yours, Butcher Boy.
Kami juga menghargaimu, Butcher Boy.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Hey, Shank,
Shank.
did you ever wonder what it would be like...
Kau pernah berpikir apa rasanya.
if someone actually did get your car?
Jika mobilmu dicuri sungguhan?
Well, I know one thing...
Yang kutahu...
whoever does will have to be the best of the best.
Pencuri itu adalah orang yang terbaik.
Good day to you, madam.
Selamat siang, Nona.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
I'm here from the, uh, Department of Noise.
Aku dari Departemen Kebisingan.
And the thing is, we've been getting some complaints
Kami mendapat keluhan.
down at HQ.
Di kantor pusat.
Uh, Larry's the one who takes the calls.
Larry yang jawab teleponnya.
Anyways, someone told Larry...
Larry diberi tahu...
that we've been hearing a lot of
Kalau ada.
gun sounds and screaming sounds...
Suara tembakan dan teriakan.
and what-have-you. That sort of thing.
Dan semacam itu.
Whoa! This is nice.
Ini bagus.
Where have you been all my life?
Dari mana saja kau selama ini?
Uh, so I came to check on things.
Aku datang untuk memeriksa.
Oh, I'm sorry, who did you say you were again?
Maaf, kau siapa?
Oh, I'm Larry?
Aku Larry?
Uh, you said Larry took the call.
Katamu Larry yang terima telepon.
Good job, Larry!
Kerja bagus, Larry!
Yeah, worked like a charm!
Sangat berhasil!
Are you kidding me? Someone got Shank's car?
Kau bercanda? Mobil Shank dicuri?
And I need yours. Sorry.
Aku butuh mobilmu. Maaf.
I'm just... I'm just gonna go.
Aku pergi saja.
This is the worst day of my life!
Ini hari terburukku!
It's a shame we have to leave so soon.
Sayang kita harus pergi.
This game is cool.
Game ini keren.
Just get us out of here
Bawa kita keluar.
so we can get this car to Spamley and get paid.
Supaya Spamley bisa membayar kita.
No problem.
Bukan masalah.
Look at this guy coming in hot.
Dia melaju cepat.
You mess with the bull, you get the horns, little girl!
Macam-macam dengan banteng kau akan terkena tanduknya.
You still have value, Butcher Boy.
Kau masih berharga, Butcher Boy.
Oh, no! It's that Shank lady.
Gawat. Itu Shank.
She looks upset.
Dia kesal.
Ah, don't worry, I'll lose her.
Tenang. Akan kuhindari dia.
Where are you going?
Ke mana kau?
Kid, get back on the track. I'm gonna lose my cookies.
Kembali ke lintasan. Aku mau muntah.
There is no track. I can drive anywhere.
Tidak ada lintasan. Semua bisa dilalui.
Oh, kid, she's coming up right behind us.
Nak, dia di belakang kita.
Oh, hello!
Halo!
I believe you have something of mine.
Kau mencuri milikku.
Yeah, come and get it.
Ya, ambillah.
This girl can drive.
Dia bisa menyetir.
Would you hurry up and lose her?
Bisa hindari dia?
I'm trying!
Sedang kucoba!
Hang on, chumbo!
Pegangan!
I don't like this!
Aku tidak suka ini!
Whoa! Mother Hubbard, this lady can really drive.
Ya ampun, dia hebat.
Kid, fire! Do you see the fire?
Nak, api! Kau tidak lihat?
Dead end! Dead end!
Jalan buntu!
Not for me. Bye-bye, Shanky.
Tidak bagiku. Dah, Shanky.
- Oh, yeah! - That's the stuff.
Ya! Itu keren.
Good job, kid.
Kerja bagus, Nak.
Oh, yeah, I feel like me again.
Aku merasa seperti diriku lagi.
One exit straight ahead.
Jalan keluar di depan.
You're not gonna lose me that easy.
Kau tidak bisa lolos semudah itu.
How did you...?
Bagaimana kau...
Uh, you might wanna keep your eyes on the road.
Sebaiknya lihat jalanan.
Kid!
Nak!
Yo, Department of Noise, get out of my car!
Departemen Kebisingan, keluar dari mobilku!
Oh, man, what are we gonna do?
Kita harus apa?
You just stay put, don't panic.
Tetap tenang.
I'm gonna talk to her.
Aku akan bicara.
Ralph, be careful.
Ralph, hati-hati.
It's fine. This is what heroes do.
Tenang. Ini tugas pahlawan.
My bottom is stuck.
Bokongku nyangkut.
This car is not designed for a big boy.
Mobil ini tidak dibuat untuk pria besar.
I'll tell you that. Hi.
Begitulah. Hai.
You guys really thought you could just steal my car?
Kalian pikir bisa mencuri mobilku?
Well, let me tell you what's gonna happen now.
Biar kuberi tahu apa yang terjadi.
No, wait, listen. We aren't normally car thieves.
Tunggu. Kami bukan pencuri mobil.
My friend here, she's a candy kart racer.
Temanku pembalap Candy Kart.
You should see her racing around
Kau harus lihat dia saat balapan.
her sweet little track...
Di lintasan permennya.
in her cookie wafer car we built together.
Dengan mobil wafer yang kami buat.
And, well, the thing is, her perfect little game broke...
Masalahnya, game-nya telah rusak.
and it was my fault...
Dan itu adalah salahku.
so we're here to try to fix it...
Jadi kami ingin memperbaikinya
and we need money to do that,
Dan butuh uang.
and someone was gonna pay us money...
Dan seseorang akan membayar.
- to steal your car... - Okay, okay.
Untuk mencuri mobilmu. Baik.
- ...and so we took it. - You can stop crying.
Jadi kami mencuri. Berhenti menangis.
Though I do respect
Aku menghormati...
your wonderful display of vulnerability.
Tampang sedihmu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
I get it, I do.
Aku mengerti.
Friendship is everything to us, too.
Persahabatan juga penting bagi kami.
- Right, guys? - Word. We're like family.
Benar? Kami seperti keluarga.
That's really great.
Itu sungguh bagus.
So, does this mean we can keep your car?
Jadi kami boleh ambil mobilmu?
Absolutely not. But I do want to help.
Tentu tidak. Tapi aku bisa membantu.
Hey, you got your phone on you?
Kau bawa ponsel?
- You know it. - Let's make a video.
Bawa. Ayo buat video.
Pyro, hit big boy with the blow and go.
Pyro, serang angin ke bocah besar ini.
I'd love to.
Dengan senang hati.
Wait. What's the...?
Tunggu. Apa...
What are you doing?
Kau sedang apa?
Say something, first thing that comes to your mind.
Katakan hal yang kau pikirkan.
I'm gonna wreck it!
Aku akan hancurkan!
Good. All right. Turn it off.
Bagus. Matikan.
What the heck did you do that for?
Untuk apa itu?
Yeah.
Ya.
There are much better ways to make money on the Internet
Banyak cara untuk mendapatkan uang di Internet.
than stealing cars...
Daripada mencuri mobil.
such as becoming a BuzzzTube star.
Seperti menjadi bintang BuzzzTube.
Am I supposed to know what that is?
Apa itu?
Oh, come on. Everybody knows BuzzzTube.
Ayolah. Semua orang tahu BuzzzTube.
It's the video-sharing site.
Itu situs berbagi video.
I'm just starting your account...
Aku membuatkan akunmu.
All right, there you go.
Itu dia.
If this thing goes viral, you can make a lot of money.
Jika ini viral, kau akan dapat banyak uang.
A friend of mine, chick named Yesss...
Temanku bernama Yesss.
she's the head algorithm over there.
Adalah kepala algoritma di sana.
Tell her I sent you.
Katakan aku yang suruh kalian ke sana.
Yesss will hook you up.
Yesss akan membantu kalian.
Wow, that's really nice of you.
Kau sungguh baik.
I'm not sure if "nice" is the right word.
Aku tidak yakin "baik" itu kata yang tepat.
Well, thank you.
Terima kasih.
I should be thanking you, little sister.
Aku yang harus terima kasih, Adik.
That race was fun.
Balapan itu menyenangkan.
Well, thank you again.
Terima kasih lagi.
While we're talking shop, what move did you do
Omong-omong, gerakan apa.
to get through that tunnel of fire?
Saat kau melewati terowongan api itu?
Was it a power drift into a drift jump, maybe, or...?
Apa itu drift kuat atau drift lompat mungkin?
Maybe.
Mungkin.
If you ever wanna come back for a rematch...
Jika kau mau tanding ulang.
I'd be happy to kick your butt again.
Aku akan mengalahkan kau lagi.
See you.
Sampai jumpa.
Show-off.
Tukang pamer.
Man, oh, man, that place was scary.
Astaga, tempat itu menakutkan.
I know. It was so exciting!
Aku tahu. Sangat menyenangkan!
No, exciting is when you smile.
Bukan, senang membuatmu senyum.
Scary is when you clench your butt,
Takut membuat bokongmu tegang.
and my butt is still clenched.
Dan bokongku masih tegang.
Oh, come on, are you honestly telling me...
Ayolah, kau pikir...
that Shank lady wasn't the coolest person you ever met?
Shank bukan orang terkeren yang pernah kau temui?
Cool? Name one cool thing about her.
Sebut satu hal yang keren darinya.
Um, let's see, she looks cool, she talks cool...
Tampangnya, ucapannya.
she drives cool, her hair is cool, her car is cool...
Balapannya, rambutnya, mobilnya keren.
Wait a minute, are you saying my hair isn't cool?
Menurutmu rambutku tidak keren?
What? No! I'm just saying the game was next-level.
Tidak! Maksudku game ini beda level.
There was no one telling you what to do or where to go.
Tidak ada yang menyuruhmu.
Hey, just where do you think you're going?
Kau mau ke mana?
To BuzzzTube. It's this way.
Ke BuzzzTube. Lewat sini.
No, no, no. We're going back to Spamley's.
Tidak. Kita datangi Spamley.
He can give us some easier loot to find.
Dia bisa carikan loot mudah.
No, we're supposed to see Shank's friend.
Tidak, kita datangi teman Shank.
Oh, come on. I don't trust that Shank one bit.
Aku tidak memercayai Shank.
- Well, I do. - Well, I...
Aku percaya. Aku...
- Hello, mister. - Who are you?
Halo, Tuan. Siapa kau?
I'm your friendly ebay alert messenger.
Aku pesan pengingat ebay.
Huh. An actual eboy.
Eboy sungguhan.
Just here to let you know your bid expires in eight hours.
Tawaranmu berakhir 8 jam lagi.
Eight hours. Okay, thanks, eboy.
8 jam. Terima kasih, eboy.
You got it, Jackson!
Sama-sama, Jackson!
Chumbo, if we nickel-and-dime it with Spamley...
Jika kita cari recehan dengan Spamley.
it will take 20 years
Akan butuh 20 tahun.
to make enough money to buy the wheel.
Untuk membeli setirnya.
All right, fine. We'll do it your way.
Baiklah. Kita ikuti caramu.
But I'm telling you right now, that BuzzzTube place
Tapi kuberi tahu, BuzzzTube itu.
is a terrible idea.
Ide yang buruk.
Man, there are all kinds of videos in here.
Banyak macam video di sini.
Yeah, if you like babies and cats.
Kalau kau suka bayi dan kucing.
- Look, there's you! - Oh, yeah.
Itu kau! Ya.
I'm gonna wreck it!
Aku akan hancurkan!
I wonder why those little guys
Kenapa orang-orang itu.
are giving your video all those hearts?
memberi hati ke video kita?
Because obviously they love me.
Karena mereka mencintaiku.
I told you this place was a good idea.
Sudah kubilang ini ide bagus.
Yeah, sure you did, doof.
Tentu saja, Bodoh.
Now, who we supposed to see about getting paid again?
Siapa yang harus kita temui?
The head algorithm. Her name is Yesss.
Kepala algoritma. Namanya Yesss.
No. No. No.
Bukan.
Uninspired, cliched...
Tidak menginspirasi, klise...
Ugh! YouTube's got this one.
Sudah ada di YouTube.
Chewbacca Dad? Really?
Ayah Chewbacca? Yang benar saja?
Yeah, it's like Chewbacca Mom, but it's a daddy.
Itu seperti Ibu Chewbacca, tapi ini ayahnya.
No!
Tidak!
Heyo! Are you the head of Al Gore?
Kau kepala Al Gore?
I am the head algorithm of BuzzzTube...
Aku kepala algoritma BuzzzTube.
which means I curate the content...
Artinya aku memilih konten.
at the Internet's most popular video-sharing site.
Di situs berbagi video terpopuler di Internet.
Which means, I don't have time to trifle...
Aku tidak bisa buang waktu.
with every shoeless, mouth-breathing hobo
Dengan gembel tidak bersepatu dan bau.
that trundles into my office.
Yang masuk ke ruanganku.
Call security, Maybe.
Panggil keamanan.
Yes. But, Yesss, this is the leaf blower guy.
Tapi itu pria yang tertiup angin.
Who?
Siapa?
The man with the undulating jowls.
Pria dengan rahang bergelombang.
So?
Lalu?
His video has 1.3 million hearts.
Videonya dapat 1,3 juta hati.
Why didn't you tell me
Kenapa kau tidak bilang.
I was in the presence of a genius?
Aku kedatangan seorang genius?
Grab him a drink.
Ambilkan dia minum.
Yeah, this lady named Shank...
Seorang wanita bernama Shank.
she actually made the video.
Yang membuat videonya.
She's the one who told us to come see you.
Kami disuruh mendatangimu.
No wonder your video's so dope.
Pantas videomu keren.
Shank is for real cool.
Shank sangat keren.
Right?
Benar.
She is not.
Dia tidak keren.
I'm the cool one getting all the hearts.
Aku yang keren karena mendapat banyak hati.
Well, that's right, you big baby.
Itu benar, bayi besar.
Yeah.
Ya.
Um, what'd you say your name was?
Siapa namamu tadi?
Ralph, Wreck-It Ralph.
Ralph, Wreck-It Ralph.
Well, Wreck-It Ralph, you are trending!
Wreck-It Ralph, kau jadi trending!
And these are for you. Hearts, hearts, hearts, hearts.
Ini untukmu. Hati, hati.
- Hearts, hearts, hearts!
Hati, hati!
Yes! Hearts!
Ya! Hati!
Uh, not to buzzkill the lovefest
Bukannya ingin menganggu.
you guys got going on here...
Diskusi kalian.
but Shank kinda told us that
Tapi Shank bilang.
viral videos can make, like, actual money?
Video viral bisa mendapatkan uang?
Oh, hearts are money, honey.
Hati adalah uang, Sayang.
Your Buzzzy account converts hearts into dollars.
Hati diubah jadi uang.
$43,000!
$43.000!
Kid, we only needed $27,001. We're done.
Kita cuma butuh $27.001. Sudah selesai.
Oh, no, no, no.
Tidak.
That's $43.
Itu $43.
43? That's not even half of 27,001.
Separuh $27.001 saja tidak sampai.
And we only have eight hours left to save my game.
Tinggal 8 jam untuk selamatkan game-ku.
Ugh. Well, I hate to say it, but that ain't happening.
Itu tidak sempat.
Your video is tapped out.
Video kalian sudah turun.
But I thought I was trenching?
Kukira aku trenching.
Trending.
Trending.
You were. But that was 15 seconds ago.
Itu 15 detik lalu.
Now, you're not.
Sekarang tidak lagi.
Thanks for stopping by, though.
Terima kasih sudah mampir.
What are we gonna do, kid?
Kita harus apa, Nak?
All right, pal, I have an idea. And hear me out.
Aku punya ide. Dengar.
What if we go back to Slaughter Race
Kita kembali ke Slaughter Race.
and I ask Shank really...
Dan minta Shank.
No, no, no. We're not going back to that death trap.
Tidak. Kita tidak akan kembali ke perangkap mematikan itu.
Yesss, what if I made you a whole bunch of videos...
Yesss, bagaimana kalau kubuatkan video.
of me doing all kinds of them crazy things?
Diriku melakukan hal-hal gila?
You mean saturate the market?
Maksudmu memenuhi pasar?
That could get you a lot of hearts fast.
Itu cepat dapat hati.
Have you thought this through at all?
Kau sudah pikirkan ini?
What do you plan on even doing in these videos?
Kau mau apa di dalam video?
I'll just copy whatever's popular.
Kutiru video populer.
Genius. Yo, Maybe, what's trending right now?
Cerdas. Apa yang sedang trending?
Mmm-hmm. Let's have a lookie-lookie.
Coba kulihat.
As usual, human suffering is number one...
Seperti biasa, penderitaan manusia menjadi nomor satu.
followed by hot pepper
Diikuti tantangan makan.
eating challenges...
Cabai pedas.
video game walkthroughs...
Main video game.
oh, screaming goats are back...
Kambing teriak kembali trending.
unboxings, cooking demos, makeup tutorials...
Unboxing, memasak, tutorial merias.
and lastly, ugh, bee puns.
Yang terakhir, plesetan lebah.
Let's "bee" friends.
Ayo berteman.
Two weeks in a row, guys.
Dua pekan berturut-turut.
That's a fortnight of bee puns.
Itu dua minggu.
He won't be doing any bee puns. They're beneath you.
Dia tidak akan lakukan itu. Mereka di bawahmu.
Oh, I'm doing a bee pun. Oh, yes, I am.
Akan kulakukan itu.
And I'm eating a hot pepper, and I'm putting on makeup...
Akan kumakan cabai pedas, merias.
and whatever else it takes!
Dan semuanya!
Because, kid, we came here to save your game
Karena kita ingin selamatkan game-mu.
and we're gonna do it.
Dan kita lakukan itu.
I love it! Ha!
Aku suka!
That is what the Internet was made for!
Ini tujuan Internet dibuat!
Now, let's get to work.
Ayo bekerja.
Seen it.
Sudah kulihat.
Saw that one.
Sudah pernah.
Huh?
RALPH ADALAH G.O.A.T.
Yo, McNeely, you remember Wreck-It Ralph?
McNeely, kau ingat Wreck-It Ralph?
That bad guy from the old video game?
Penjahat di video game?
Yeah, exactly.
Ya.
I'm gonna send you a super random video.
Akan kukirim videonya.
Check it out, dude.
Lihatlah.
Yeah, I'll give it a heart. Whatever.
Aku akan beri hati.
Hey, everybody, welcome to Up To the Meme-ent!
Selamat datang di Up To the Meme-ent!
I'm your host, Dani Fernandez.
Aku host kalian, Dani Fernandez.
Nobody knows who's making them,
Entah siapa pembuatnya.
but the whole world is going bonkers...
Tapi seluruh dunia tergila-gila.
over a series of truly bizarre videos...
Dengan rangkaian video aneh.
starring '80s-era bad guy Wreck-It Ralph.
Berisi penjahat era 1980, Wreck-It Ralph.
Check out what everyone is buzzing about...
Lihat yang dibicarakan orang.
over at BuzzzTube.com.
Di BuzzzTube.com.
Hey, guys, Wreck-It Ralph here...
Hei, ini Wreck-It Ralph.
with the ghost pepper challenge.
Dengan tantangan cabai hantu.
Supposed to be spicy. We'll see about that.
Mestinya pedas. Kita lihat nanti.
Mmm. That's not so...
Itu tidak...
Oh, it's very hot! Oh, make it stop!
Pedas sekali! Hentikan!
Yo, McNeely, another one just dropped.
McNeely, video lain baru diunggah.
Check it out, dude.
Lihatlah.
Where are these things coming from?
Dari mana video ini?
Hey, Josey,
Hei, Josey.
did you see the pepper challenge?
Sudah lihat tantangan cabai?
Oh, not yet.
Belum.
I'm watching the one where he just smacks his lips.
Aku nonton saat dia mengunyah.
It's disgusting.
Itu menjijikkan.
You don't want any real hard lines.
Garisnya jangan terang.
You just want to blend that out there, like this...
Campur saja semua seperti ini.
And that, my friends,
Dan itu.
is how you achieve the perfect cat eye.
Adalah cara mendapatkan mata kucing sempurna.
I always start
Aku selalu mulai.
with the hootnanny. Shift it into a floss.
Dengan Hootenanny. Ganti dengan Floss.
And now I finish with a hot Marat. Huh? Huh?
Selesaikan dengan Hot Marat.
Follow along with me,
Ikuti aku...
and I'm gonna give this little cloud a little friend...
Dan kuberi awan ini teman kecil.
in the form of a tree.
Dalam bentuk pohon.
Everybody needs a friend.
Semua orang butuh teman.
Look at these guys.
Lihat ini.
Look at this one, sleeping under his ear.
Lihat dia, tidur di bawah telinga.
You couch potatoes. Wake up.
Bangunlah, Pemalas.
We've been baking at about 950 degrees
Kita sudah panggang di 950 derajat.
now for six hours...
Selama enam jam.
so she should be ready.
Jadi ini sudah matang.
Voila! Burnt pie!
Pai gosong!
Let's have a little whiff of this here.
Kita cium sedikit.
My hair, my hair! My hair!
Rambutku!
This man is on fire.
Dia terbakar.
Literal and figurative fire.
Baik rambutnya maupun semangatnya.
But he still needs 200 million hearts
Tapi dia butuh 200 juta hati.
in the next five hours...
Dalam 5 jam.
or this beautiful child loses her game.
Atau anak cantik ini akan kehilangan gamenya.
That's why I'm on to phase two...
Itu sebabnya kuubah ke fase dua.
you, my elite Pop-Up Army.
Yaitu kalian pasukan Pop-Up.
I need you out there popping up...
Pergi ke luar sana...
and getting clicks all over the Internet.
Dan cari klik di Internet.
I'm talking Tumblr, Instagram, Mashable.
Mulai dari Tumblr, Instagram, Mashable.
Be my pied pipers and
Aku ingin kalian pancing dan...
lead that beautiful traffic to BuzzzTube...
Arahkan pengguna ke BuzzzTube.
because Wreck-It Ralph needs his hearts.
Karena Wreck-It Ralph membutuhkan hatinya.
Hey, mister! Hey, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, you, you.
Hei, Tuan! Ya, kau.
You don't wanna miss this.
Kau tidak mau melewatkan ini.
It's the latest Wreck-It Ralph video.
Video Wreck-It Ralph terbaru.
Click it. Click it!
Kliklah!
Man oh Manischewitz, that looks so fun.
Ya ampun, itu tampak menyenangkan.
Yesss, can I be a pop-up?
Yesss, boleh aku jadi pop-up?
I don't know. Can you be annoyingly aggressive?
Entahlah. Kau bisa jadi agresif dan menyebalkan?
I don't know. Can I? Can I? Can I?
Entahlah. Boleh? Boleh?
Oh, yes, you're perfect. Here.
Ya, kau sempurna. Ini.
Thank you!
Terima kasih!
If you're going, I wanna go.
Kalau kau pergi, aku ikut.
No, baby, you've got to stay here and be my movie star.
Tidak, kau tetap di sini dan jadi bintangku.
What? No, no, no. Me and the kid are like shoes and socks.
Tidak. Aku dan dia seperti kaos kaki dan sepatu.
Or peanut butter and bacon.
Atau selai kacang dan dendeng.
One cannot exist without the other.
Saling membutuhkan.
Go on, kid, tell her.
Katakan padanya, Nak.
It's true.
Itu benar.
In fact, it's so true that we will be fine
Sebenarnya, kami akan baik baik saja.
if we're apart for a minute.
Kalau berpisah sebentar.
Come on, pal. It's my game we're trying to save.
Ayolah. Kita sedang coba selamatkan game-ku.
I just wanna get out there and be useful.
Aku ingin berguna di luar sana.
But without me?
Tanpa aku?
What if you get lost? You're just a kid.
Kalau kau tersesat? Kau masih anak-anak.
Oh, and you're some mature adult?
Kau sudah dewasa?
Well, I'm bigger.
Aku lebih besar.
Don't be insecure, big fella.
Jangan cemas, Kawan.
She's not gonna get lost. I promise.
Dia tidak akan tersesat. Aku janji.
She'll be in my personal web browser.
Dia akan ada di browser web pribadiku.
And your app comes with BuzzzFace...
Aplikasimu terhubung dengan BuzzzFace.
so you can keep in touch anywhere on the Internet.
Jadi kau bisa komunikasi di Internet.
See, I'll be fine.
Aku akan baik baik saja.
I know, I just...
Aku tahu. Aku...
We haven't been apart in like six years.
Kita tidak terpisah selama 6 tahun.
I'm going to miss you.
Aku akan merindukanmu.
You'll be fine, too.
Kau akan baik baik saja.
The more hearts your videos get,
Semakin banyak hati yang kau dapat.
the faster we'll get the wheel.
Semakin cepat kita dapat setir.
And then we can go home.
Lalu kita bisa pulang.
Look, we'll be celebrating
Kita akan rayakan.
at Tapper's this time tomorrow, buddy.
Di Tapper's besok, Kawan.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Ya, kurasa kau benar.
Bye!
Dah!
Be careful, huh? Don't be a dummy.
Hati-hati, ya? Jangan bertingkah bodoh.
So where exactly are you sending her?
Ke mana kau mengirimnya?
Since candy girl comes from an arcade game...
Karena gadis permen dari game Arcade.
I'm thinking she'd be good in the gaming district.
Kurasa dia bagus di distrik game.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Bad idea.
Tidak. Ide buruk.
Those games are dangerous, and they rot your brain.
Game itu berbahaya dan membusukkan otak.
Why don't we send her somewhere
Kita kirim dia ke tempat.
a little more totally different than that...
Yang lebih berbeda.
and nowhere near there?
Dan jauh dari itu.
Let's see. Family Friendly Fansites.
Biar kulihat. Family Friendly Fansites.
That sounds safe, and she is technically a princess...
Itu terdengar aman dan dia juga seorang putri.
so how about this one here
Jadi bagaimana kalau.
with the sweet little pink castle?
Istana merah muda yang lucu ini?
I love it.
Aku suka.
Okay, I'll redirect our newest pop-up to OhMyDisney.com.
Akan kuarahkan dia ke OhMyDisney.com.
Jeez Louise, this place is bonkers! Whoa!
Ya ampun, tempat ini gila sekali!
To infinity and beyond!
Menuju tidak terbatas dan melampauinya!
Aw, come on. Princesses and cartoon characters?
Yang benar saja. Putri dan karakter kartun?
Lame.
Payah.
Hey, easy there.
Tenang.
Oh, I mean, no offense or anything.
Tidak bermaksud untuk menyinggung.
Well, time to get to work.
Waktunya kerja.
And for your final question.
Untuk pertanyaan terakhir.
"My friends would describe me as?"
"Temanku menggambarkanku sebagai?"
"Smart, funny, kind, or brave."
"Pintar, lucu, baik, atau berani."
Kind, I guess?
Baik, kurasa?
Based on your answers, your princess BFF is
Berdasarkan jawabanmu, sahabat putrimu adalah...
Snow White!
Snow White!
I do believe our friendship
Aku yakin persahabatan kita...
will be the fairest of them all!
Adalah yang paling baik!
Hey, wanna meet my BFF? It's Wreck-It Ralph.
Mau bertemu sahabatku? Namanya Wreck-It Ralph.
Just click here to see his new video.
Klik di sini untuk lihat video barunya.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Yeah, um, in Captain America: The First Avenger...
Dalam Captain America: The First Avenger.
Red Skull refers to Yggdrasil,
Red Skull bicara soal Yggdrasil.
the World Tree, Guardian of Wisdom and Fate.
Pohon Dunia, Pelindung Kebajikan dan Takdir.
Are we to believe, sir,
Apa Anda...
that you are a descendant of that tree?
Keturunan dari pohon itu?
I am Groot.
Aku Groot.
Okay, okay. Thank you very much.
Baik. Terima kasih banyak.
Um, what is Drax really like?
Bagaimana sifat Drax?
- I am Groot. - Thank you.
Aku Groot. Terima kasih.
Yeah. Are you a conifer or a fruit-bearing tree?
Apa kau tumbuhan runjung atau pohon buah?
- I... - Excuse me.
Aku... Permisi.
I'll take this one. He is Groot,
Biar kujawab. Dia Groot.
I am Vanellope,
Aku Vanellope.
click here to meet Wreck-It Ralph.
Klik di sini untuk bertemu Wreck-It Ralph.
Eh, this is almost too easy.
Ini mudah.
Hey, do you have a permit for that pop-up?
Kau punya izin untuk pop-up?
That's unauthorized clickbait. You're coming with us, kid.
Itu ilegal. Ikut kami, Nak.
She's getting away.
Dia kabur.
This way.
Sebelah sini.
Sorry, mister!
Maaf, Tuan!
Hey, can't you read? Cast members only!
Kau tidak baca? Khusus pemeran!
I think she went down this way. Come on.
Kurasa dia ke sini. Ayo.
Roger that.
Baik.
Did you see a kid come through here?
Lihat anak kecil lewat sini?
She came running through here like a headless hen.
Dia lari keluyuran di sini.
Any sign of her?
Ada tanda dia?
No, maybe she went down
Tidak, mungkin dia ke...
to the Air Bud pavilion.
Paviliun Air Bud.
Come on. Let's check it out.
Ayo periksa.
Uh, hi!
Hai!
Whoa, whoa. Ladies, I can explain.
Nona-nona, aku bisa jelaskan.
See, I'm a princess, too.
Aku juga seorang putri.
- Wait, what? - Yeah.
Apa? Ya.
Princess Vanellope Von Schweetz...
Putri Vanellope Von Schweetz.
of the, uh, Sugar Rush Von Schweetzes.
Dari Sugar Rush Von Shweetzes.
I'm sure you've heard of us.
Kalian pasti tahu kami.
It'd be embarrassing for you if you haven't.
Kalau tidak tahu itu memalukan.
Huh. What kind of a princess are you?
Kau putri apa?
What kind?
Putri apa?
- Do you have magic hair? - No.
Rambutmu ajaib? Tidak.
- Magic hands?
Tangan ajaib?
- Do animals talk to you? - No.
Bicara dengan binatang? Tidak.
- Were you poisoned? - No!
Kau diracuni? Tidak!
- Cursed?
Dikutuk?
- Kidnapped or enslaved? - No!
Diculik atau diperbudak? Tidak!
Are you guys okay? Should I call the police?
Kalian baik baik saja? Mau kutelepon polisi?
Then I have to assume you made a deal
Pasti kau buat perjanjian.
with an underwater sea witch...
Dengan penyihir laut dalam.
where she took your voice
Suaramu diambil...
in exchange for a pair of human legs?
Untuk ditukar dengan kaki manusia?
No! Good Lord, who would do that?
Tidak! Siapa yang lakukan itu?
Have you ever had True Love's Kiss?
Kau pernah dapat ciuman cinta sejati?
Ew! Barf!
Jorok!
Do you have daddy issues?
Kau berantem dengan ayahmu?
I don't even have a mom.
Ibu saja aku tidak punya.
Neither do we!
Kami juga!
And now for the million-dollar question.
Untuk pertanyaan sejuta dolar.
Do people assume all your problems got solved
Semua orang berpikir masalahmu selesai.
because a big strong man showed up?
Karena pria besar dan kuat muncul?
Yes! What is up with that?
Ya! Kenapa begitu?
She is a princess!
Dia seorang putri!
Who made your gown?
Siapa pembuat gaunmu?
I've never seen anything quite like it.
Aku tidak pernah lihat yang begini.
Oh, this old thing?
Gaun lama ini?
Oh, I'd so love to have one of my own.
Aku mau punya yang begini.
- As would I. - Me too!
Aku juga.
- So cool. - Best outfit ever!
Keren sekali. Pakaian terbaik!
Ooh! I want one, too, you guys!
Aku juga mau!
I'll get my mice on this.
Tikusku akan kupakaikan ini.
So this is love.
Jadi ini namanya cinta.
All hail Princess Vanellope, the queen of comfy!
Putri Vanellope hebat, ratu kenyamanan.
Yay, Vanellope!
Ya, Vanellope!
Of all the thingamabobs in this entire world...
Dari semua hal di dunia.
I never thought I'd get to wear a real...
Tidak kusangka aku akan memakai.
what's it called again?
Apa namanya?
Oh, yeah. Shirt.
Kaos.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait! What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
Uh, she's singing.
Dia bernyanyi.
Yeah, but there was like music and a spotlight.
Ya, tapi ada musik dan lampu sorot.
Wait, you all saw it too, right?
Kalian lihat juga, 'kan?
That's what happens
Itu terjadi...
when a princess sings about her dreams.
Saat seorang putri menyanyikan mimpi mereka.
Oh, that's never happened to me. I mean, not even once.
Aku tidak pernah mendapat yang seperti itu.
Why don't you give it a try?
Kenapa tidak coba?
What is it you really want? Sing about that.
Apa keinginanmu? Nyanyikan itu.
Okay. Uh, sure.
Baik.
Huh. I could do that. Um, let's see.
Aku bisa. Biar kucoba.
Well, there is a lot to unpack here.
Banyak yang harus kita bahas.
So, this steering wheel you sing of,
Jadi setir yang kau nyanyikan.
that's a metaphor?
Apa itu metafora?
Oh, no, no, no, it's not a metaphor. I just...
Bukan metafora. Aku hanya...
I literally want a steering wheel.
Aku ingin setir sungguhan.
I think the issue is I was a little pitchy.
Kurasa masalahnya aku sedikit sumbang.
Maybe a little.
Mungkin sedikit.
But sometimes your song can't start...
Tapi kadang lagumu tidak bisa mulai...
until you go someplace to reflect.
Sampai kau bercermin.
What works for some of us...
Sebagian dari kami...
is finding a form of water and staring at it.
Menatap ke air.
What?
Apa?
Oh, yes, I like to stare at a wishing well!
Ya, aku suka menatap ke sumur harapan!
I stare at the ocean.
Aku menatap laut.
Horse trough.
Wadah minum kuda.
Soap bubbles!
Busa sabun!
Wait, you're saying if I just stare at some water...
Jika aku menatap air...
Uh, important water.
Air penting.
Right. Of course. "Important water."
Tentu saja. "Air penting."
I stare at the important water...
Aku menatap air penting...
and somehow magically I'll start singing about my dream?
Dan secara ajaib aku nyanyikan impianku?
- For sure. - Mmm-hmm.
Benar.
Uh, yeah, I don't think so, ladies, but thanks.
Kurasa tidak, tapi terima kasih.
Five minutes, Princesses.
Lima menit lagi, Tuan Putri.
Another "Which Disney Princess Are You?" quizlet
Kuis "Putri Disney Manakah Anda?".
starts in five minutes.
Akan mulai lima menit lagi.
Okay, thank you.
Terima kasih.
Well, I guess it's back to the gowns, girls.
Kembali pakai gaun, Teman-teman.
It was lovely to meet you, Vanellope.
Senang menemuimu, Vanellope.
And best of luck finding your song.
Semoga berhasil menemukan lagumu.
What did she just say?
Dia bilang apa?
We don't know. We can't understand her.
Entahlah. Kami tidak mengerti dia.
She's from the other studio.
Dia dari studio lain.
Hi, everybody. Wreck-It Ralph here...
Hai, semua. Ini Wreck-It Ralph.
with a little box I'm gonna open.
Yang akan membuka kotak kecil.
Let's see what we got here.
Coba lihat ini.
A "Pancake Milkshake Fun Set." Huh.
"Koleksi Kue Dadar dan Susu Kocok."
Got a little heft to it.
Sedikit berat.
Something wobbling around in there.
Ada yang bergetar.
Wonder if we got the kitty or the bunny.
Entah kita dapat kucing atau kelinci.
Let's open it up.
Mari kita buka.
Man, who would've guessed a bee pun
Siapa sangka plesetan lebah.
would be the thing to put us over the top?
Bisa jadi trending?
Huh. That's the Internet for you.
Itulah Internet.
All right, it is uploading.
Sedang diunggah.
Hey, mister!
Hei, Tuan!
Oh. Hi, eboy.
Hai, eboy.
Just here to let you know
Hanya ingin mengingatkan...
your bid does expire in 30 minutes.
Kalau tawaranmu akan berakhir 30 menit lagi.
Thanks, little eboy.
Terima kasih, eboy kecil.
You got it, chairman.
Sama-sama, Bos.
You hear that, Yesss?
Dengar itu, Yesss?
We don't have a lot of time left.
Waktu kita tidak banyak.
Okay. We just gotta...
Kita harus...
No, no, no.
Tidak.
No! Not you!
Jangan kau!
What? Why are you angry at the lollipop?
Kenapa kau marah pada lolipop?
What does that mean?
Apa artinya?
The file's not loading.
File-nya tidak memuat.
If this doesn't load, we're not gonna make it.
Jika tidak memuat, kita tidak akan berhasil.
- Hmm. - You don't have enough hearts.
Hatimu tidak cukup banyak.
Ralph, where are you going?
Ralph, kau mau ke mana?
I'm going down to the floor to get some hearts.
Aku mau kumpulkan hati.
Ah! Genius! Good thinking.
Cerdas!
Now, someone get me tech support in here, stat!
Panggilkan bantuan teknis ke sini!
Only one person.
Cuma satu orang.
Hey, guys, come and check out my video,
Hei, ayo lihat videoku.
you're gonna love it.
Kalian pasti suka.
Right, right over here. Yep, here we go.
Sebelah sini.
What are you... You guys!
Apa yang kalian...
Aw. A cat?
Kucing?
You're gonna like this better than some dusty old cat.
Kalian pasti suka ini daripada kucing tua.
What?
Apa?
Give me that hose, partner.
Berikan selang itu.
You know you love me, give me those hearts. There we go.
Kalian suka aku. Berikan hati kalian.
Hey, folks, where are you going? Give my video a heart.
Kalian mau ke mana? Beri videoku hati.
That's it. Let's see who's in here.
Itu dia. Kita lihat siapa di dalam.
Hello?
Halo?
Anybody in here?
Ada orang?
What the heck is this place?
Tempat apa ini?
Some kind of libary?
Semacam perpustakaan?
"Wreck-It Ralph is back."
"Wreck-It Ralph kembali."
Hey, they're talking about me.
Mereka membicarakanku.
Gee whiz, the Internet is so positive.
Ya ampun, Internet sangat positif.
"Fix-It Felix, Jr. was my favorite game."
"Fix-It Felix, Jr. adalah game kesukaanku."
Hmm. Mine, too.
Aku juga.
"Ralph's videos stink."
"Video Ralph payah."
What?
Apa?
"So stupid."
"Bodoh sekali."
"Ralph is the worst."
"Ralph sangat buruk."
"I hate him."
"Aku benci dia."
"He's so fat and ugly."
"Dia gendut dan jelek."
"Just a worthless bum, alone on a pile of bricks."
"Cuma gelandangan di atas batu bata."
Yo, Ralph, you in here, dude?
Ralph, kau di dalam?
Hey, I got to show you...
Aku harus tunjukkan...
First rule of the Internet...
Aturan pertama di Internet.
do not read the comments.
Jangan baca komentar.
I should have told you that.
Mestinya kuberi tahu.
Look.
Dengar.
This place can bring out the worst in some people...
Ada sisi terburuk manusia di sini.
but you gotta ignore all this.
Tapi kau harus abaikan.
This isn't about you, Ralph. It's about them.
Masalahnya bukan padamu. Tapi mereka sendiri.
I don't care. It's fine.
Aku tidak peduli. Tidak masalah.
People hated me my whole life for being the bad guy.
Orang-orang membenciku karena jadi penjahat.
It's just a good reminder
Itu pengingat yang baik.
that this is the only heart
Bahwa hanya hati ini.
that really matters.
Yang penting.
Vanellope gave me this...
Vanellope memberikan ini...
and as long as she likes me...
Dan selama dia menyukaiku.
I don't need anybody else.
Aku tidak butuh orang lain.
And I sure don't need the Internet.
Aku yakin tidak butuh Internet.
Hold on.
Tunggu.
It's not all bad.
Semuanya tidak buruk.
The Internet can also be a place...
Internet bisa jadi tempat.
where you find a steering wheel at one website...
Kau bisa temukan setir di situs web.
and make enough money to buy it at another one.
Dan mendapat uang untuk membelinya.
Congratulations, Ralph. You did it.
Selamat, Ralph. Kau berhasil.
Wait, really?
Sungguh?
Yes, check your Buzzzy account.
Ya, periksa akun Buzzzy-mu.
You needed 27K, you got over 30 grand!
Kau butuh 27.000. Kau sudah dapat 30.000 lebih.
Oh, my gosh!
Astaga!
This is great!
Ini hebat!
Thank you, Yesss. I couldn't have done it without you!
Terima kasih, Yesss. Semua berkat bantuanmu.
That's really true.
Itu memang benar.
Hey, eboy?
Hei, eboy?
What do you need, ace?
Kau butuh apa?
Can you give me a ride?
Bisa beri tumpangan?
Let's hop along, Cassidy.
Ayo naik.
Come on, song, come on.
Ayolah, lagu.
I'm reflecting.
Aku sedang bercermin.
What is it that I want?
Apa yang kuinginkan?
What is my quest?
Apa yang kucari?
What is my dream?
Apa impianku?
Well, ladies, I tried.
Teman-teman, sudah kucoba.
No song for this princess, I guess.
Tidak ada lagu untukku.
How does this thing work?
Bagaimana caranya?
Hey, kid, can you see me?
Hei, Nak, kau lihat aku?
Yeah! Yeah, you're right there.
Ya, kau di sana.
We did it! We got the money!
Kita berhasil! Kita dapat uangnya!
No way, Ralph! That's great!
Tidak mungkin, Ralph! Itu bagus!
I'm on my way to ebay right now with the eboy.
Aku menuju ebay dengan eboy.
We're almost there, champ.
Kita hampir sampai.
Good work, eboy.
Kerja bagus, eboy.
Hey, meet me out in front of ebay in five minutes, okay?
Temui aku di depan ebay lima menit lagi.
Okay, I'll see you soon.
Baik. Sampai jumpa.
We're going home, kid!
Kita akan pulang, Nak!
Our lives can finally get back to normal.
Hidup kita bisa kembali normal.
Wow, I can't believe it. I get to go home.
Tidak kusangka. Aku akan pulang.
So, I guess that's it.
Kurasa ini akhirnya.
I guess I just wanted a... a steering wheel.
Kurasa aku mau setir.
And now, I got it, so...
Aku sudah dapat, jadi...
Slaughter Race?
Slaughter Race?
Do you wanna get rich playing video games?
Mau kaya dengan main game?
Click here to...
Klik di sini untuk...
Oh. Ralph. Ralph! Hey, there.
Ralph. Hei.
Oh, hey, Spamley.
Hei, Spamley.
What's the good word, brother?
Apa kabar baiknya?
Well, the good word is I just paid for the steering wheel...
Aku baru bayar setirnya...
and we are going home.
Dan kami akan pulang.
Congratulations.
Selamat.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Hey, have you seen Vanellope anywhere?
Kau lihat Vanellope?
Oh, uh, your little chum? Uh, no, no, I haven't.
Sahabat kecilmu? Aku tidak melihatnya.
Hope she's not lost.
Kuharap dia tidak tersesat.
Let me try to reach her on this doohickey.
Biar kuhubungi dia dengan alat ini.
See over there? Over that mountain?
Lihat di atas gunung itu?
- Yeah. - That's the Sequoia Speedway.
Ya. Itu Lintasan Sequoia.
It's gonna be unlocked next month.
Akan dibuka bulan depan.
Hey, what are you doing in that awful game with her?
Sedang apa kau di game buruk itu?
I think the track will end...
Lintasannya akan berakhir...
right over there. Yo, it's gonna be so tight.
Di sana. Pasti sangat keren.
Oh, I love it.
Aku suka.
Hey, can I tell you something
Bisa kuberi tahu hal...
that I don't think I could ever tell Ralph?
Yang tidak bisa kukatakan pada Ralph?
Of course.
Tentu.
I know it sounds crazy...
Ini terdengar gila.
but the second I walked into this game, it felt...
Tapi sesaat aku masuk game ini, aku merasa...
Well, it felt like home.
Game ini terasa seperti rumah.
I mean, more than Sugar Rush ever did.
Lebih dari Sugar Rush.
Oh, yeah? How so?
Kenapa begitu?
'Cause it's like my dream.
Karena ini impianku.
It's full of weirdos...
Penuh dengan orang aneh.
and the racing is super dangerous...
Balapannya sangat berbahaya.
and you never know what's gonna happen next.
Dan tidak bisa diprediksi.
I mean, back home,
Di rumahku.
I know exactly what's gonna happen next...
Aku tahu yang akan terjadi selanjutnya.
because Ralph's dream is to do the same thing every day.
Karena impian Ralph yaitu mengulang aktivitas.
Here's something I wish I'd learned years ago.
Kuharap aku mempelajari ini dahulu.
There is no law
Tidak ada aturan.
saying best friends have to have the same dreams.
Yang menyebut impian sahabat itu sama.
You know?
Kau tahu?
Yeah.
Ya.
You are a very wise person, Shank.
Kau sangat bijak, Shank.
And a good friend, too.
Dan juga teman yang baik.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Around here, peeps like to say, "Shank you."
Orang-orang sering bilang, "Shank you".
You know, after you go home
Setelah kau pulang...
and your life gets back to normal...
Dan hidupmu kembali normal.
you are always welcome here.
Kau selalu diterima di sini.
But that's the thing, I want this to be my normal.
Itu masalahnya, aku ingin ini jadi normalku.
I want this to be my life.
Aku ingin ini jadi hidupku.
I can't go home now.
Aku tidak bisa pulang.
I just can't.
Tidak bisa.
You know, where I come from,
Di tempat asalku.
that's called a kick in the face.
Itu disebut dengan pukulan telak.
I can't believe it.
Aku tidak percaya.
A straight-up donkey kick to the teeth.
Pukulan telak ke gigi.
She's supposed to be my best friend.
Mestinya dia sahabatku.
No, this can't be right.
Ini tidak mungkin.
No, she's been brainwashed.
Dia sudah dicuci otak.
That's what this is.
Itu masalahnya.
Because the Vanellope I know
Vanellope yang kukenal.
would never abandon me like that.
Tidak akan meninggalkanku begitu.
I gotta get her out of there now.
Aku harus keluarkan dia.
Hey, easy now, tiger.
Tenang.
I admire the impulse...
Kukagumi keinginanmu.
but you charge in there like some white knight...
Tapi kalau kau tiba-tiba masuk.
she's liable to hold it against you.
Dia akan melawanmu.
So what? I'm supposed to just let her stay in a game
Jadi kubiarkan dia di game itu.
that's obviously bad for her?
Yang buruk untuknya?
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
Then how do I make her leave?
Bagaimana kubuat dia pergi?
She thinks it's so cool and exciting in there.
Dia pikir di sana keren dan asyik.
Unless you know how I can make the game boring or...
Kecuali kau tahu cara buat game itu membosankan.
Wait. You know about viruses and stuff, right, Spamley?
Kau tahu soal virus, Spamley?
- Who's asking? - Whoa.
Siapa yang tanya?
Back home, me and the kid
Di tempat asalku, kami...
used to goof off in this game called Tron.
Sering membuang waktu di game bernama Tron.
But then it got a virus that made the motorbikes go slow...
Lalu ada virus yang membuat motornya lambat.
and then Vanellope stopped wanting to hang out in there.
Dan Vanellope tidak mau ke sana lagi.
So, is there a way
Adakah cara...
to do something like that to Slaughter Race?
Untuk melakukan itu ke Slaughter Race?
Oh, there's ways.
Ada banyak cara.
Follow me.
Ikuti aku.
I got mothers' maiden names...
Aku punya nama gadis ibu.
social security numbers, PIN numbers...
Nomor jaminan sosial, nomor PIN.
Now, this area down here
Tempat ini...
is what's called the Darknet.
Bernama Darknet.
A lot of shady characters hang out down here...
Banyak karakter rahasia di sini.
so try to keep a low profile. Gord!
Jadi jangan mencolok. Gord!
Oh, there you are.
Kau di sana.
Now Gord here, he's dabbled in virus-making.
Gord berkecimpung dalam pembuatan virus.
But his cousin, this guy we're gonna go see...
Tapi sepupunya yang akan kita temui.
Double Dan, this dude is a virus-making machine.
Double Dan adalah mesin pembuat virus.
Oh, oh, here we go.
Ini tempatnya.
Are you sure this is safe?
Kau yakin ini aman?
Is it safe? Of course it is.
Aman? Tentu saja.
Just whatever you do, do not look at his little brother.
Tapi jangan tatap adiknya.
Oh, he has a little brother?
Dia punya adik?
Double Dan!
Double Dan!
Long time no see.
Lama tidak berjumpa.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
JP Spamley.
JP Spamley.
Uh, we met one time over at Friendster...
Kita pernah ketemu sekali di Friendster.
which tells you it had to be a long time ago.
Yang berarti itu sudah lama sekali.
- Oye. What are you looking at? - Nothing.
Kau lihat apa? Tidak ada.
Are you looking at my brother?
Kau melihat adikku?
- No, sir. - Don't you look
Tidak, Pak. Jangan lihat...
at my little brother.
Adikku.
- Oh, no, I wasn't. - He's very self-conscious!
Tidak. Dia pemalu!
You?
Kau?
What are you doing here?
Sedang apa di sini?
The reason I came to your neck of the face...
Alasan aku datang ke wajah lehermu.
I mean, there's a face in your neck. I mean, woods.
Maksudku, ada wajah di lehermu.
Neck of the woods. The reason I'm here is 'cause I...
Di tempatmu. Alasan aku datang adalah...
Well, I heard a little tumor, rumor...
Kudengar sedikit tumor, rumor.
I heard a rumor that you could, well,
Rumornya kau bisa...
give me a harmless virus kind of thing...
Memberi virus tidak berbahaya.
that might be able to
Yang bisa.
slow down the Slaughter Ra game?
Memperlambat game Slaughter Race?
Oh, yeah.
Ya.
My cousin Gordon told me that you wanted to crash it.
Gordon bilang kau mau merusaknya.
Crash it? No!
Tidak!
No, no, no.
Tidak.
I don't want anyone getting hurt.
Aku tidak ingin ada yang terluka.
If there's a way to just, uh...
Jika ada cara untuk...
I don't know...
Entahlah.
just make the cars go slow or something...
Membuat mobilnya melambat.
so the game is boring...
Supaya game-nya jadi membosankan.
and my friend comes back home to me.
Dan temanku ikut pulang denganku.
Allow me to introduce you to Arthur.
Kuperkenalkan Arthur.
Easy there, boy.
Tenang.
He's keen.
Dia bersemangat.
Arthur's what I call an insecurity virus.
Arthur adalah virus kecemasan.
Means he looks for little flaws and weaknesses
Dia mencari celah dan kelemahan.
that make a program insecure.
Yang membuat program tidak aman.
You release him into that Slaughter Race game,
Lepaskan dia di Slaughter Race.
Arthur will find some defect in the code.
Arthur akan temukan kecacatan di kode.
Then he'll copy that defect
Dia akan salin kecacatan itu.
and spread it all over the game...
Dan menyebarkannya ke seluruh game.
until everything becomes, quote, unquote, "boring"...
Sampai semua menjadi "membosankan".
just like you wanted.
Seperti yang kau mau.
Okay.
Baik.
Just to be super clear here...
Biar kuperjelas lagi.
no one gets hurt, right?
Tidak akan ada yang terluka, 'kan?
Are you stupid?
Kau bodoh?
Because the only way anyone gets hurt...
Karena orang lain akan terluka.
is if you are stupid.
Kalau kau bodoh.
All you have to do...
Kau hanya perlu...
is make sure the virus stays in Slaughter Race.
Memastikan virusnya tetap berada di Slaughter Race.
Right. Don't be stupid.
Baik. Jangan bodoh.
Make sure it doesn't get out of Slaughter Race.
Pastikan tidak keluar dari Slaughter Race.
Goiter it. Gah!
Papan.
- Got it! Got it. - Get out!
Paham! Keluar!
Thank you, you're a cyst face.
Terima kasih, wajah kista.
- Out! - I mean, assistance.
Maksudku, bantuan.
Thank you for your cyst face... Assistance.
Terima kasih atas bantuan kistamu.
- Get out! - Goodbye!
Keluar! Selamat tinggal!
Ah! Fiddlesticks! Well, that's game.
Sial! Kau menang.
Ah, beginner's luck.
Keberuntungan pemula.
Come on, kid. I know a hustle
Ayolah, Nak. Kau lincah.
- Player's on the way. - Thanks, Bob.
Pemain datang. Terima kasih, Bob.
- Let's roll! - Game faces on, guys.
Ayo beraksi! Wajah fokus, Teman.
Show time. You ready for your first race?
Waktunya beraksi. Siap untuk balapan pertamamu?
Um, yeah. I think so.
Ya, kurasa.
Hey, don't be nervous. You're gonna be great.
Jangan gugup. Kau akan baik baik saja.
Yeah, no, I know. I'll be fine.
Ya, aku tahu. Ini akan baik baik saja.
Mmm. You didn't tell Ralph yet, did you?
Kau belum beri tahu Ralph, 'kan?
Not exactly.
Tidak juga.
Come on, V. He's your best friend.
Ayolah, V. Dia sahabatmu.
You gotta let him know
Beri tahu dia...
you're planning on staying here for a while.
Kau mau tinggal sementara di sini.
I know. But he's gonna get really upset.
Aku tahu, tapi dia akan kesal.
Yeah, he might, but you guys...
Mungkin, tapi kalian...
you'll talk, you'll work it out, you'll figure it out.
Bicara, selesaikan, cari solusi.
Yeah, but what if we don't?
Bagaimana kalau tidak begitu?
What if his feelings get hurt so bad...
Bagaimana kalau dia sangat sakit hati.
he won't wanna be my friend anymore?
Dan tidak mau berteman denganku lagi?
Look. All friendships change...
Persahabatan itu berubah.
but the good ones...
Tapi persahabatan yang baik.
they get stronger because of it.
Semakin erat karena perubahan.
Uh, Shank, I hate to bother you...
Shank, bukan ingin ganggu.
but the player is waiting.
Tapi pemain sudah menunggu.
I'm not gonna tell you what to do, kid.
Aku tidak akan menyuruhmu, Nak.
It's your call.
Ini keputusanmu.
Yeah, okay.
Baik.
Let's race.
Ayo balapan.
Scanning for insecurities.
Memindai kecemasan.
"Precious Car-go."
"Barang Berharga."
Deliver the car to Bert's Chop Shop...
Antar mobil ke Bengkel Bert.
but watch out for Shank and her crew.
Tapi waspadai Shank dan kru-nya.
Power drift into a drift jump!
Drift kuat ke drift lompat!
I saw it! You're amazing!
Aku melihatnya! Kau hebat!
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Scanning for insecurities.
Memindai kecemasan.
Looks like we're not finished. Come on, V.
Sepertinya belum selesai. Ayo, V.
Ralph?
Ralph?
Okay. Relax. Relax!
Baik. Tenanglah.
I'll just call him after the race.
Akan kutelepon dia setelah balapan.
It'll be okay.
Ini akan baik baik saja.
Ralph will be fine.
Ralph akan baik baik saja.
Insecurity detected.
Kecemasan terdeteksi.
Copying insecurity.
Menyalin kecemasan.
Distributing insecurity.
Menyebar kecemasan.
Distributing...
Menyebar kecemasan. Menyebar.
What is happening?
Apa yang terjadi?
What's going on, Spamley?
Ada apa ini, Spamley?
The whole place is going crazy.
Tempat ini menggila.
I thought that virus was just supposed to slow down her car.
Kukira virusnya hanya memperlambat mobil.
It was.
Memang.
It must've found something real unstable in there.
Dia pasti menemukan ketidakstabilan di sana.
It's her glitch.
Itu Glitch-nya.
Game reboot begins
Reboot game mulai.
in 60 seconds.
Dalam 60 detik.
Whoa, hey! Hey, Ralph, you can't go in there.
Ralph, kau tidak boleh masuk.
They're gonna reboot the game...
Game-nya akan reboot.
and anything that doesn't belong in there
Dan semua yang tidak dibuat di dalam.
will be deleted.
Akan dihapus.
Yeah, and if I don't get her outta there,
Jika tidak kukeluarkan dia.
Vanellope's gonna die!
Vanellope akan mati!
Come on, kid. The game's crashing. Let's go.
Ayo, Nak. Game-nya rusak.
I think it's my glitch.
Kurasa karena Glitch-ku.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to destroy your game.
Maaf, aku tidak bermaksud hancurkan game-mu.
We'll be fine, but your code isn't part of this game.
Kami akan baik saja, tapi kodemu bukan bagian dari game ini.
We got to get you out of here now. Follow me to the exit.
Kau harus keluar. Ikuti aku ke pintu keluar.
Oh, no, no!
Tidak!
Kid!
Nak!
Kid, where are you?
Di mana kau?
The server is rebooting, Ralph.
Servernya reboot, Ralph.
Both of you have to get out of here now.
Kalian harus keluar.
Kid, I got you. I got you.
Nak, aku menemukanmu.
Game reboot...
Game reboot.
in five, four, three...
Dalam lima, empat, tiga.
two, one.
Dua, satu.
Reboot in progress.
Reboot dalam proses.
Come on, Vanellope. Wake up.
Ayo, Vanellope. Bangunlah.
Come on. Don't leave me, kid.
Jangan tinggalkan aku, Nak.
Ralph?
Ralph?
Oh. There you are. You okay, kid?
Kau sadar. Kau baik baik saja, Nak?
Ralph, I messed up so bad.
Ralph, aku mengacau.
No. No, you didn't, it's okay.
Kau tidak mengacau. Tenang.
This is all because of me and my glitch.
Ini karena aku dan Glitch-ku.
I should've just stayed with you...
Mestinya aku tinggal denganmu.
instead of following some stupid dream.
Daripada mengejar impian bodohku.
I've ruined everything.
Aku merusak semuanya.
No, kid, no.
Tidak, Nak.
Ah, look. I didn't mean for it to happen like this.
Aku tidak bermaksud jadi seperti ini.
It was not supposed to be this bad.
Mestinya tidak seburuk ini.
You didn't mean for what to happen?
Kau tidak bermaksud apa?
I mighta, kinda sorta put a...
Aku mungkin meletakkan...
harmless little virus in the game.
Virus tidak berbahaya ke dalam gamenya.
A virus?
Virus?
You did this?
Kau pelakunya?
I wouldn't have done anything
Aku tidak akan lakukan apapun.
if I hadn't heard you tell Shank...
Kalau tidak mendengar percakapanmu.
that you wanted to live in Slaughter Race forever.
Kalau kau ingin tinggal di Slaughter Race.
So you were spying on me?
Kau memata-mataiku?
Hey. You're not exactly innocent here.
Kau sama bersalahnya.
You were gonna ditch everybody and abandon Sugar Rush.
Kau akan tinggalkan semua orang dan Sugar Rush.
Oh, please. I'm one of 16 racers.
Yang benar saja. Pembalapnya ada 16.
They'd never miss me.
Mereka tidak akan merindukanku.
What about me?
Aku bagaimana?
Why would I ever spend another second with you...
Untuk apa aku habiskan waktu denganmu.
after what you did?
Setelah yang kau sudah lakukan?
No!
Tidak!
No.
Tidak.
Vanellope, where are you going?
Vanellope, kau mau ke mana?
Wherever you're not.
Menjauhi dirimu.
Wait a minute. I can explain.
Tunggu. Aku bisa jelaskan.
No! You will not follow me.
Tidak! Jangan ikuti aku.
Vanellope, please...
Vanellope, kumohon...
A friend would never do what you did. Never!
Teman tidak akan lakukan perbuatanmu tadi!
So you leave me alone!
Tinggalkan aku sendiri!
Vanellope, no, no, no! Please!
Vanellope, tidak! Kumohon!
Please! What did I do?
Kumohon! Apa yang sudah kuperbuat?
Scanning for insecurities.
Memindai kecemasan.
Vanellope, come on, don't leave me!
Vanellope, jangan tinggalkan aku!
Insecurity detected.
Kecemasan terdeteksi.
Copying insecurity.
Menyalin kecemasan.
Oh, no, no, no.
Tidak.
Distributing insecurity.
Menyebar kecemasan.
Come on.
Ayolah.
Where is it?
Di mana benda itu?
Oh, no.
Gawat.
You are such an idiot.
Kau bodoh sekali.
What is your problem, Ralph? I told you, don't follow me.
Ada apa denganmu? Kubilang, jangan ikuti aku.
Friend?
Teman?
Cut that out. You're scaring me.
Hentikan itu. Kau menakutiku.
- Friend! - Huh? Whoa!
Teman!
- What the...? - Friend?
Apa-apaan... Teman?
Friend!
Teman!
Sweet mother of Ralph!
Ya ampun!
In breaking news,
Berita terkini.
the Internet is under assault...
Internet diserang.
as a massive denial-of-service attack...
Dengan serangan DoS.
crashes servers across the web.
Yang merusak seluruh server.
The Wreck-It Ralph virus
Virus Wreck-It Ralph.
is fast-moving and destructive.
Bergerak dengan cepat dan merusak.
Friend? Huh?
Teman?
Experts are still trying to understand who or what
Para ahli masih mencari penyebab dan apa.
the virus's intended target may be.
Target dari virus ini.
Friend.
Teman.
Friend!
Teman!
I found 130 results for
Kutemukan 130 hasil untuk...
"Where does my high school girlfriend live now?"
"Di mana lokasi pacar SMA-ku sekarang?"
You're welcome.
Sama-sama.
- Mr. KnowsMore! - Hmm.
Tn. KnowsMore!
Oh, delightful!
Senang sekali.
You're that courteous little cherub
Kau malaikat kecil...
who says "please" and "thank you."
Yang bilang "tolong" dan "terima kasih".
What can KnowsMore help you find today?
Apa yang bisa KnowsMore carikan?
There's a whole...
Ada banyak...
Whole Foods, a hole in the ozone...
Whole Foods, lubang di ozon.
A Whole Lotta Love by British rockers Led Zeppelin?
A Whole Lotta Love oleh Led Zeppelin?
No! No! There's a whole bunch of Ralphs chasing me.
Bukan! Ada banyak Ralph mengejarku.
Friend...
Teman...
This would probably be an appropriate time
Mungkin ini waktu yang tepat.
for me to shutter my site.
Untuk tutup situs.
How long you think
Berapa lama...
before they get in here?
Sampai mereka bisa masuk?
Precisely one second.
Tepat satu detik.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hei!
It's me! It's the real me!
Ini aku yang asli!
- Ralph? - My apologies.
Ralph? Maaf.
I followed those things here.
Aku mengikuti mereka.
I think they're looking for you, kid.
Kurasa mereka mencarimu, Nak.
Yeah, you think? What did you do?
Masa? Apa yang kau perbuat?
I'm so sorry. I don't how this happened.
Maaf. Entah kenapa jadi begini.
Well, I think it's fairly obvious.
Kurasa cukup jelas.
It happened because an insecurity virus cloned...
Ini terjadi karena virus kecemasan meng-klon.
all of your needy, clingy, self-destructive behavior.
Sikap manja, menyebalkan, dan tukang hancur.
The very behavior which left unchecked
Sikap-sikap itu...
can destroy friendships...
Bisa menghancurkan pertemanan.
and in this particular case, the entire Internet!
Dan kasus sekarang, seluruh Internet!
KnowsMore! You have all the answers.
KnowsMore. Kau tahu jawabannya.
Official query...
Pertanyaan resmi.
what do I do if clones of me
Aku harus apakan klon diriku.
are trying to capture my friend? Search.
Yang coba menangkap temanku? Cari.
I find two results for your query.
Kutemukan dua jawaban.
Either you put all the clones in therapy.
Beri terapi pada semua klon.
Not very realistic.
Tidak realistis.
Or, the anti-virus district is surrounded
Atau distrik anti-virus dikelilingi.
by a gate made from security software.
Gerbang dari software keamanan.
If Vanellope could somehow
Jika Vanellope bisa...
lead all of the clones through the gate...
Arahkan semua klon melewati gerbang.
they would be deleted all at once.
Mereka semua akan terhapus.
Sort of a co-dependent pied piper situation.
Semacam memancing mereka.
Wait. We know a pied piper.
Kita tahu ahlinya.
- We do? - Yesss.
Masa? Yesss.
- Who? - Yesss!
Siapa? Yesss!
Yeah, but who is it?
Ya, tapi siapa?
Oh, you mean Yesss!
Maksudmu Yesss!
Thanks for your help, KnowsMore.
Terima kasih atas bantuanmu, KnowsMore.
It's a bit of an empty gesture at this point,
Sebenarnya bantuan itu tidak disengaja.
Guess I forgot to tell Ralph
Aku lupa beri tahu Ralph...
that when you break the Internet...
Saat sukses di Internet.
you don't literally have to break the Internet.
Bukan berarti menghancurkannya.
I can't believe he did this.
Tidak kusangka dia melakukan ini.
Yeah, well, I mean, dude obviously made
Dia membuat...
some real questionable choices here.
Pilihan yang membingungkan.
But he also made a bee pun to save his best friend's game...
Tapi dia rela tersiksa demi selamatkan game temannya.
so what can I say, kid, life's complicated.
Jadi hidup itu memang rumit.
You ready to pied the piper?
Kau siap untuk memancing?
Yoo-hoo! Up here!
Di atas sini!
It's me, your bestest friend in the whole wide world...
Aku sahabat kalian...
who you can't live without!
Yang tidak bisa kalian tinggalkan!
Friend!
Teman!
Wow, from up here I can see how I do come across as...
Dari sini aku bisa lihat betapa...
needy, and clingy,
Manja, menyebalkan.
and self-destructive like KnowsMore said.
Dan perusaknya aku.
Listen, kid...
Dengar, Nak,...
I don't blame you
Aku tidak menyalahkanmu.
for not wanting to be my friend anymore.
Karena tidak ingin jadi temanku lagi.
I never said I didn't want to be your friend.
Aku tidak bilang begitu.
I said you were acting like a bad friend. Which you were.
Aku bilang tingkahmu seperti teman yang buruk.
I know I was, but I...
Aku tahu, tapi...
Hey, my babies!
Hei!
That's the anti-virus district straight ahead. Whoo!
Itu distrik anti-virusnya!
All right, to be continued, okay?
Kita lanjutkan nanti, ya?
Whoo-hoo! We're gonna make it!
Kita akan berhasil!
You guys okay?
Kalian baik baik saja?
I'm fine!
Aku baik baik saja!
Yeah, all good. Look, we can still do this.
Ya, baik baik saja. Kita masih bisa lakukan ini.
Come on, big man. Help me turn this thing over.
Ayo, pria besar. Bantu balikkan ini.
Uh, guys?
Teman-teman?
Friend?
Teman?
That is unsettling.
Itu aneh.
Friend.
Teman.
Get Vanellope out of here now.
Bawa pergi Vanellope.
What about you, Ralph?
Kau bagaimana, Ralph?
Just go. I got a date with the man in the mirror.
Pergilah. Aku mau kencan dengan kembaranku.
Hey, you!
Hei, kau!
You keep away from her!
Jauhi dia!
I'm gonna wreck it!
Aku akan hancurkan!
She's not your friend!
Dia bukan temanmu!
She's my friend!
Dia temanku!
Here it is, this way.
Sebelah sini.
Come on, kid. We gotta move.
Ayo, Nak. Kita harus cepat.
Eeeee-oh-boy!
Eeeee-oh-boy!
No!
Tidak!
Vanellope!
Vanellope!
Hey! Let go of me!
Lepaskan aku!
- Kid! - Ralph!
Nak! Ralph!
Hey!
Hei!
Hey, get back here!
Kembalilah!
You put her down!
Turunkan dia!
Vanellope!
Vanellope!
You know, you're acting like a real bad guy here!
Tingkahmu seperti penjahat!
No!
Tidak!
Well, you are!
Itu benar!
And I will never be your friend!
Dan aku tidak mau jadi temanmu!
Hey, doofus!
Hei, Bodoh!
Ralph!
Ralph!
Catch me if you can, you big dummy!
Tangkap aku, raksasa bodoh!
I got you, little sister.
Aku menangkapmu, Adik.
Now go! Get out of here!
Pergilah!
- Ralph! - Go!
Ralph! Pergi!
No! Don't hurt him!
Tidak! Jangan sakiti dia!
Please, no!
Kumohon, jangan!
Stop it! You're squishing him!
Hentikan! Kau meremukkannya!
You're gonna kill my best friend!
Kau akan membunuh sahabatku!
Fine! You win! You win, okay?
Baik! Kau menang!
Just please put him down.
Turunkan dia.
I'll be your only friend, okay?
Aku akan jadi temanmu, ya?
Just let him go.
Lepaskan dia.
No! No, kid.
Tidak, Nak.
That's it. That's it. Yeah.
Itu dia.
Put him down and I'll go with you...
Turunkan dia dan aku akan ikut denganmu.
and we'll be best friends forever.
Dan kita akan bersahabat selamanya.
Just me and you.
Hanya kita berdua.
That's what you want, right?
Itu maumu, 'kan?
Well, that's not what I want!
Itu bukan mauku!
It's not right to hold a friend back from her dreams!
Salah kalau menahan teman dari impiannya!
You don't own her!
Dia bukan milikmu!
That's not how friendship works!
Bukan begitu pertemanan!
You need to let her go!
Kau harus merelakannya!
Hey.
Hei.
You need to let her go.
Kau harus merelakannya.
I know. It's gonna hurt a little bit when you do.
Aku tahu itu akan sedikit sakit.
Oh, who am I kidding? It's gonna hurt a lot.
Itu akan sangat sakit.
But you're gonna be okay.
Tapi kau akan baik baik saja.
And we're gonna be okay.
Kita akan baik baik saja.
Right, kid?
Benar, Nak?
Of course we are. Always.
Tentu saja.
See? No matter where she goes...
Lihat? Ke manapun dia pergi...
or where she lives...
Atau tinggal.
she's always gonna be our friend.
Dia akan selalu menjadi teman kita.
And we just gotta trust her.
Kita harus memercayainya.
Because that's what best friends do.
Karena itu yang sahabat lakukan.
Right?
Benar?
Thanks, buddy.
Terima kasih, Kawan.
I feel good about this.
Aku merasa lega.
Ralph, look!
Ralph, lihat!
I think you fixed your insecurity!
Kau memperbaiki kecemasanmu!
You're right.
Kau benar.
Ralph, no!
Ralph, tidak!
Park it right here, Ralph!
Ayo ke sini, Ralph!
Your ol' pal JP Spamley's gotcha!
Teman lamamu JP Spamley membantumu!
Wow, that didn't work.
Itu tidak berhasil.
Look up there!
Lihat ke atas!
It's a big strong man in need of rescuing.
Pria kuat besar butuh bantuan.
Oh, thanks, Frogger.
Terima kasih, Katak.
Wait a minute.
Tunggu dulu.
Who are all of you?
Siapa kalian?
We're friends of Vanellope's.
Kami temannya Vanellope.
Yeah, and any friend of Vanellope's
Semua teman Vanellope...
is a friend of ours.
Adalah teman kami.
You're welcome.
Sama-sama.
Ralph!
Ralph!
Looking good, big fella!
Kau tampak tampan, Kawan!
Heyo!
Hei!
This dress is not made for a big boy.
Gaun ini bukan untuk bocah besar.
It's going right up the back alley there.
Langsung robek di belakang.
Let me just make a little adjustment.
Biar kuatur sedikit.
There we go.
Itu dia.
Internet users are breathing
Pengguna Internet.
a collective sigh of relief tonight.
Bisa bernapas lega malam ini.
Just as mysteriously as it appeared,
Sama misteriusnya saat muncul.
the Wreck-It Ralph virus has vanished.
Virus Wreck-It Ralph telah menghilang.
You know what I just realized?
Kau tahu yang kusadari?
The sun never rises or sets here...
Matahari tidak pernah terbit atau terbenam di sini.
because everything's always on.
Karena semuanya selalu menyala.
Well, now, isn't that an astute observation?
Pengamatan yang cerdik.
I know, right?
Benar.
You know, other than KnowsMore,
Selain KnowsMore.
I'm probably the smartest guy on the Internet.
Aku mungkin orang terpintar di Internet.
Yeah. Yeah.
Ya.
Yo, V. We're about to come back online. You ready?
V, kami mau online. Kau siap?
Be right there!
Aku menyusul!
Hey, Ralph, don't be a stranger!
Ralph, jangan sungkan.
Well, I can't be much stranger than you, Shank.
Aku tidak lebih sungkan dibanding kau, Shank.
Oh. That's a good dad joke.
Itu lelucon ayah yang bagus.
Hey, don't forget.
Jangan lupa.
You know Shank added my code and everything,
Shank menambahkan kodeku ke dalam gamenya.
so I'll be able to regenerate.
Jadi aku bisa hidup kembali.
I'm gonna be totally safe.
Aku akan aman.
No, I know. It's gonna be great.
Aku tahu. Itu pasti hebat.
You found your dream game.
Kau temukan game impianmu.
Yeah, I did.
Ya.
I did.
Benar.
So, uh...
Jadi...
I guess I should probably head in there now, you know?
Kurasa aku harus masuk.
Oh, before you go, I wanted to give you this.
Sebelum pergi, aku mau berikan ini.
Oh, I'm so sorry I broke it, Ralph.
Maaf aku mematahkannya, Ralph.
No, no. It's okay.
Tidak apa.
Now we can both have a half. See?
Kita bisa dapat separuhnya.
Yeah!
Ya.
I love you so much.
Aku sangat menyayangimu.
I'm really gonna miss you.
Aku akan merindukanmu.
I'm gonna miss you too, kid.
Aku juga, Nak.
I really am.
Sungguh.
All right.
Baik.
Okay, getting a little clingy on me, here.
Kau jadi manja.
Go on. Get out of here.
Pergilah.
The world's waiting for you, kid.
Dunia menunggumu, Nak.
I'll be honest,
Aku akan jujur.
it still feels kind of weird around here.
Masih terasa aneh di sini.
I mean, a lot has changed.
Banyak yang berubah.
Even though we got that steering wheel
Meski kami dapat setirnya...
and saved Sugar Rush...
Dan menyelamatkan Sugar Rush.
it's never really gonna be the same.
Ini tidak akan sama.
For one thing, the racers aren't even
Contohnya, pembalap jadi...
that obnoxious anymore.
Tidak menyebalkan lagi.
Oh, golly. I'm sorry you didn't win, Taffyta.
Maaf kau tidak menang, Taffyta.
Pfft! Our friendship is much more important to me
Pertemanan kita lebih penting.
than winning, Rancis.
Daripada menang, Rancis.
Losing builds character!
Kalah membangun karakter!
Everyone's a winner, Taffyta.
Semuanya menang, Taffyta.
Felix and Calhoun,
Felix dan Calhoun.
as goofy as they are,
Walau mereka bodoh.
they turned out to be pretty great parents.
Ternyata bisa jadi orangtua yang hebat.
I gotta hand it to you two,
Kalian hebat.
how on earth did you tame those things?
Bagaimana kalian melakukan itu?
It's simple, Surge.
Sederhana, Surge.
The key to parenting is...
Kunci dari mengasuh anak...
And then what you do is...
Lalu kau lakukan...
And that is the secret to raising perfect children.
Itu rahasia membesarkan anak yang sempurna.
Wow, I wish every parent could hear that.
Seandainya semua orangtua mendengar itu.
I'm keeping busy, too.
Aku juga tetap sibuk.
I finally joined Zangief's book club.
Aku bergabung dengan klub buku Zangief.
Good point, Bison. And how about you, Ralph?
Poin bagus, Bison. Kau bagaimana, Ralph?
Do you feel Dostoyevsky
Kau merasa Dostoyevsky.
intended to make narrator unreliable?
Bermaksud membuat narator tidak dipercaya?
I do and I don't.
Aku setuju dan tidak.
You do, and you don't.
Kau setuju dan tidak.
Duality. That's really deep, Ralph.
Dualitas. Itu sungguh dalam, Ralph.
Thanks, Sonic.
Terima kasih, Sonic.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
Entah apa yang kubicarakan.
Oh. And we got this new thing we do every Friday night...
Kami ada acara baru tiap Jumat malam.
where we all go and hang out in a different game.
Di mana kami berkumpul di game lain.
I actually hosted this week.
Aku jadi tuan rumah minggu ini.
Heyo!
Hei!
Hope you're all hungry. I made burnt pie.
Kuharap kalian lapar. Aku membuat pai gosong.
What's burnt pie, Wreck-It?
Apa itu pai gosong, Wreck-It?
Oh, it's just a pie that you burn.
Cuma pai yang gosong.
You can use any pie.
Bisa pakai pai apapun.
You just leave it in the oven too long.
Tinggalkan saja di oven agak lama.
Yeah, we really do have a lot of fun.
Ya, kami bergembira.
I guess that's pretty much all the news I got for you.
Kurasa hanya itu kabar untukmu.
Oh, man, your stories never disappoint, Ralph.
Ceritamu tidak pernah mengecewakan, Ralph.
I just wish we could hang out sooner.
Kuharap kita bisa bertemu secepatnya.
Yeah. Me, too.
Ya, aku juga.
When did you say you were getting those days off?
Kapan kau libur?
Uh, our upgrade starts on January 25th,
Perbaharuan kami mulai 25 Januari.
so, like, two months from now.
Jadi dua bulan mulai sekarang.
Oh, that'll go by in a flash. Oh, speaking of which...
Itu akan cepat berlalu. Omong-omong.
you want me to bring you anything from home
Kau mau kubawakan apa dari rumah.
when I come visit?
Saat aku berkunjung?
Oh! You know what I cannot find
Kau tahu yang tidak bisa kutemukan.
anywhere on the Internet?
Di Internet?
A halfway decent BurgerTime burger.
Roti burger dari BurgerTime.
I've been talking them up to Shank and the crew.
Aku terus membicarakannya dengan Shank dan kru.
And honestly, I think they're starting to think
Kurasa mereka pikir...
I'm making it up.
Aku mengarangnya.
All right, consider it done.
Baik, kucatat.
I'll bring you guys a truckload.
Akan kubawa banyak.
Well, sun's coming up already.
Matahari sudah terbit.
Guess I better get to it.
Aku harus pergi.
Yeah, me too.
Ya, aku juga.
Talk next week?
Ngobrol lagi minggu depan?
I shall await your call, madam.
Kutunggu teleponmu, Nona.
Then, adieu, adieu, farting is such sweet sorrow.
Selamat tinggal. Perpisahan itu menyedihkan.
So long, stinkbrain.
Sampai nanti, Bau.
Bye, kid.
Dah, Nak.
Hey. You doing okay there, Ralph?
Kau baik baik saja, Ralph?
Yeah, I am, actually. I'm doing great.
Ya. Aku merasa luar biasa.
Come on, Felix. Let's get to work, buddy.
Ayo bekerja, Felix.
Hey, Mo, did you like the movie, sweetie?
Mo, kau suka filmnya?
Well, there was a scene in the trailer...
Ada adegan di trailer.
that wasn't in the movie...
Yang tidak ada di film.
and that makes me sad.
Dan itu membuatku sedih.
Aw, that's too bad.
Sayang sekali.
Maybe playing your game will cheer you up.
Mungkin bermain game akan menghiburmu.
Okay.
Baik.
Pancake.
Kue dadar.
Milkshake.
Susu kocok.
Ooh, ooh, ooh. I wanna try, I wanna try!
Aku mau coba!
My turn, my turn!
Giliranku!
Pancake. Milkshake.
Kue dadar. Susu kocok.
I'm starting to understand why people like this game.
Aku paham kenapa orang suka game ini.
Very zen.
Sangat menenangkan.
Hey, everybody, look what I found!
Hei, semua, lihat yang kutemukan!
- More pancakes! - Sweet!
Kue dadar lagi! Bagus!
Let's speed it up. Pancake, pancake, pancake.
Ayo percepat. Kue dadar.
Eat, little bunny. Eat, eat, eat!
Makan, kelinci kecil!
Uh, Ralph, you might wanna try feeding the kitty
Ralph, coba beri makan kucing.
for a little while.
Untuk sekarang.
No, the kitty gets the milkshake.
Tidak, kucing dapat susu kocok.
The bunny gets the pancake.
Kelinci dapat kue dadar.